<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>City of Tulsa Current Job Openings</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 16:59:34 CST
                </pubDate><generator>Umbraco</generator><description>Current Job Openings at the City of Tulsa</description><language>en</language><item><title>Call Center Manager-Customer Care</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/call-center-manager-(1).aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/call-center-manager-(1).aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision is responsible for managing, supervising and coordinating activities of workers providing telephone customer relations services and performs other related assigned duties.
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 2246-0002SN<br />
Customer Care, Call Center<br />
Pay Grade: EX-44 / Salary Range:
$1,902-$3,635/bi-weekly.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
<strong><span>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</span></strong>Proactively manages the operations at the Call
Center (CC), ensuring adherence to established policies, quality
standards and volume metrics<br />
<br />
Studies, develops and maintains standardized operational
procedures, focusing on delivering improved operational efficiency
to meet overall City objectives<br />
<br />
Provides tools and information for customer service reps and
monitors service levels to ensure compliance with expected call
volume and quality standards<br />
<br />
Performs overall direction, coordination, planning and assigning of
CC activities, maintaining harmony among workers and resolving
grievances<br />
<br />
Negotiates appropriate service level agreements with customer
departments and agencies<br />
<br />
Forecasts call volumes and manpower requirements and monitors
statistics to ensure and maintain appropriate service levels and
control costs<br />
<br />
Adjusts necessary changes to staffing based on daily, seasonal or
other anticipated events<br />
<br />
Monitors system changes, analyzing impact on system documentation
and making revisions as needed<br />
<br />
Maintains appropriate call distribution to ensure effective
utilization of customer service representatives<br />
<br />
Investigates incidents, complaints and conflicts,
minimizing/resolving repetitive/complex problems<br />
<br />
Coordinates, assigns and supervises CC Supervisors and
Representatives' activities, determining work procedures and
preparing schedules to expedite workflow<br />
<br />
Answers questions and takes corrective actions to address customer
complaints<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Qualifications:<br />
</span></strong>Graduation from an accredited college or university
with a bachelor's degree in business administration or related
field and six (6) years of progressively responsible experience
managing a customer contact center, or related management
experience; or an equivalent combination of training and experience
per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section 128.</p>

<p>Considerable knowledge of the function and operation of a Call
Center; considerable understanding of the operation and use of data
processing/communications and related equipment; and knowledge of
principles and practices of supervision.&nbsp;&nbsp; Ability to
effectively write reports, business correspondence and procedure
manuals; ability to effectively present information; ability to
apply advanced mathematical concepts for statistical analysis;
ability to solve practical problems dealing with multiple variables
in situations with limited or no standardization; ability to
interpret a variety of instructions furnished in written, verbal,
diagram or scheduled form; and the ability to utilize the highest
level of interpersonal skill in order to understand, select,
develop and motivate people at any level within or outside the
organization.</p>

<p><strong><span>Physical Requirements:<br />
</span></strong>Physical requirements include arm and hand
steadiness and finger dexterity enough to use a keyboard and
telephone; occasional carrying up to 5 pounds; may be subject to
sitting for extended periods of time, walking, standing, sitting,
reaching, bending, kneeling, handling and twisting; and vision,
speech and hearing sufficient to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Licenses and Certificates:<br />
</span></strong>Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's
License.</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</span></strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily indoors in an
office setting and may require irregular work hours.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Electronics Technician III</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/electronics-technician-iii.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/electronics-technician-iii.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision supervises and/or participates in the installation, maintenance, and repair of various devices and related electronic controls and equipment, and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 4263-0011RKV<br />
Water &amp; Sewer, Water Pollution Control<br />
Pay Grade: AT-28 / Salary Range: $15.63 - $29.87/Hr.<br />
<br />
<strong>Essential Job Functions:&nbsp; (All
Departments/Divisions)<br />
</strong>Supervises and/or participates in the work of subordinate
Electronics Technicians engaged in a variety of installation,
maintenance, repair, and calibration activities<br />
<br />
Performs maintenance and repair work<br />
<br />
Orders parts and maintains a parts inventory<br />
<br />
Supervises and/or trains individuals concerning operations or
equipment<br />
<br />
Supervises and/or participates in the testing of controllers and
related electronic equipment<br />
<br />
Maintains a routine maintenance program of control equipment<br />
<br />
Prepares reports for departmental management<br />
<br />
Develops and maintains training manuals and charts for electronic
equipment maintenance<br />
<br />
Maintains files and records<br />
<br />
Operates light to heavy automotive equipment and/or a City
vehicle<br />
<br />
In addition to the above tasks, the following essential tasks may
be required by the individual department/division.</p>

<p><strong>Traffic<br />
</strong>Designs, modifies, and builds special equipment related to
the testing and operation of traffic control signals<br />
<br />
Supervises and performs modifications of traffic control systems at
field locations on existing control systems<br />
<br />
Programs communications, microprocessor based equipment<br />
<br />
Maintains various databases</p>

<p><strong>Airport<br />
</strong>Inspects, maintains, repairs, and troubleshoots the
operation of exterior security access gates and interior motorized
gates at both Tulsa International Airport and RL Jones Riverside
Airport<br />
<br />
Programs communications, microprocessor based equipment</p>

<p><strong>Zoo<br />
</strong>Designs, modifies, and builds special equipment related to
the testing and operation of zoo exhibits<br />
<br />
Sets up equipment for special events<br />
<br />
Writes computer programs</p>

<p><strong>Plant/Utilities<br />
</strong>Troubleshoots and repairs electrical, electro-mechanical,
hydraulic and pneumatic instrumentation systems, modules, and
controls in a water or wastewater plant or related facility<br />
<br />
Operates and adjusts pumping systems<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</strong>Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Educational Development Certificate (GED), supplemented by
successful completion of an approved two (2) year course in
electronics or other related field; and four (4) years of
experience in field and/or bench repair of electronic equipment and
related process control equipment; or an equivalent combination of
training and experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures,
Section 128.&nbsp; <strong>*Programmable</strong> <strong>Logic
Controller knowledge</strong> <strong>and experience is
preferred.</strong></p>

<p>Considerable knowledge of the operating principles of a variety
of electronic, electrical, electro-mechanical, hydraulic, and
pneumatic equipment; considerable knowledge of the tools,
equipment, methods, and materials, used in the testing, maintenance
and repair of such equipment; and considerable knowledge the theory
and operating principles of solid state devices and
circuitry.&nbsp; Ability to plan, organize, and supervise the work
of<br />
subordinates; ability to read and work from wiring diagrams,
schematics, engineering specifications, and factory service
manuals; ability to perform technical diagnostic repair work;
ability to maintain inventory and work records; ability to perform
assignments independently with limited supervision; and the ability
to utilize the highest level of interpersonal skill in order to
understand, select, develop, and motivate people at any level
within or outside the organization.&nbsp; Skill in the use of
various tools and equipment in the repair and maintenance of
electrical and electronic equipment and plant process controls and
instrumentation.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Physical requirements include arm and hand steadiness and
finger dexterity enough to use a keyboard and telephone and to
solder and de-solder miniature components on circuit boards;
occasional lifting, carrying, pushing, and pulling up to 60 pounds;
may be subject to extended periods of walking and standing;
reaching, balancing, bending, kneeling, crawling, handling,
feeling, climbing, smelling, and twisting; and vision, speech, and
hearing sufficient to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Possession of an Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License;
and some positions within this classification may be required to
obtain a valid applicable Commercial Driver's License (CDL) or a
Class "C" Water or Sewer Operator's License as issued by the
Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) within six months to one
year of hire date.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Test Required:<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered for each position.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:<br />
</strong>Working environment is indoors and outdoors and in
inclement weather;&nbsp; may be exposed to the following: hazardous
materials, animal waste/dead animals, flammable liquids, traffic,
cramped work areas, excessive dust, weather/temperature extremes,
trench excavations, underground gas/electric/petroleum lines, rough
terrain, hazardous/toxic atmospheres, damp/wet surfaces, snow/ice
covered surfaces, overhead power lines, toxic fumes/vapors/odors,
confined spaces, compressed gases, high noises, and computer
monitor.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Engineer-Special Projects</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/engineer-special-projects.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/engineer-special-projects.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ We are seeking an experienced Civil Engineer to work in our Engineering Services Department. The Engineer will be working as a Project Manager overseeing Consultant design of vertical construction projects. Experience in structural design, parking lots and trails preferred. Roofing experience would be a plus. Excellent written and verbal communication skills are required. Candidate must have extensive experience of successfully managing the schedules and budgets of multiple projects simultaneously.  Be able to work both independently and a team approach.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 4756-0003SN<br />
Engineering, Special Projects<br />
Pay Grade: EX-28 - EX-44&nbsp;</p>

<p>Engineering positions are part of a progression which means that
we will fill the vacant position commensurate with the selected
candidate's training and experience.&nbsp; <strong>*We prefer to
hire an experienced civil engineer with structural
background,</strong> <strong>will be working as a Project Manager
overseeing Consultant design of vertical construction projects.
Experience in structural design, parking lots and trails preferred.
Roofing experience would be a plus.</strong></p>

<p><strong>ENGINEER I (EX-28)&nbsp; to&nbsp; SENIOR ENGINEER
(EX-44)</strong><br />
Pay Grade:<br />
EX-28 - Engineer
I&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; $1,250 - $2,389/bi-weekly.<br />
EX-32 - Engineer
II&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; $1,383 - $2,643&nbsp;&nbsp;Requires
EIT Certification<br />
EX-36 - Engineer III&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; $1,534 -
$2,930&nbsp;&nbsp;Requires EIT Certification<br />
EX-40 - Professional Engineer&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;$1,722 -
$3,290&nbsp;&nbsp;Requires PE Certification<br />
EX-44 - Senior
Engineer&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
&nbsp;&nbsp; $1,902 - $3,635&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Requires PE
Certification</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:</strong><br />
Graduation from an accredited college or university with a
bachelor's degree in civil, electrical, or mechanical engineering;
prefer one (1) year of related engineering to requiring experience
to ten (10) years, depending on level.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:</strong><br />
Certification within Oklahoma as an Engineer Intern as evidenced by
successful completion of the Fundamentals of Engineering
examination within one year of appointment or Professional Engineer
in the State of Oklahoma and some positions require possession of a
valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License, depending on the level
requirement.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Tests Required:</strong><br />
Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be administered as
needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Working environment is primarily indoors in an office setting and
occasionally outdoors and in inclement weather and requires some
travel to various City locations to conduct fieldwork.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Engineering Technician II</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/engineering-technician-ii.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/engineering-technician-ii.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision performs a variety of technical engineering and surveying work and other related duties that may be assigned.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 4991-0020RKV<br />
Engineering Services, Field Engineering<br />
Pay Grade: AT-32 / Salary Range: $17.29 - $33.04/Hr.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>Designs, drafts (using CADD), analyzes, and plans for
Public Works projects in accordance with accepted standards and
specifications</p>

<p>Determines location, size, elevation, and grade of water and
sanitary sewer lines</p>

<p>Lays out improvements, including geometry</p>

<p>Reviews and prepares as-built drawings of Public Works projects
for computer file</p>

<p>Writes and executes contracts</p>

<p>Computes quantities of materials used in estimates and
construction of Public Works projects</p>

<p>Works with Legal Department on interpretation of legal
descriptions for ownership and encroachments</p>

<p>Requests and reviews surveys by utilities, consultants, and
other City agencies for compliance with State of Oklahoma Minimum
Standards for Surveys</p>

<p>Operates various computer software, including word processing,
database, Cogo, CADD, project planner and scheduler, and GIS</p>

<p>Supervise data collection and data entry</p>

<p>Negotiates and coordinates with utilities for location</p>

<p>Enforces technical City ordinances</p>

<p>Conducts field inspections, investigations, and evaluations of
various projects</p>

<p>Prepares preliminary cost estimates for proposed engineering
projects</p>

<p>Assists in preparation and report of capital budget</p>

<p>Prepares project status reports</p>

<p>Must report to work on a regular and timely basis</p>

<p>Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.<br />
<br />
<strong>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</strong>Graduation from an accredited college or university with
an associate's degree in pre-engineering, and four (4) years of
progressively responsible and varied subprofessional engineering
work experience; or an equivalent combination of training and
experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section
128.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Comprehensive knowledge of the principles, practices, methods,
and techniques of subprofessional engineering; considerable
knowledge of mathematics required to perform engineering
calculations; considerable knowledge of construction techniques;
good knowledge of various related software packages; good knowledge
of surveying. Ability to design Public Works projects; ability to
perform engineering calculations; ability to interpret and enforce
technical ordinances and regulations; and the ability to
courteously and tactfully communicate with fellow workers,
supervisors, other members of the organization and the public in
giving and receiving information.<br />
<br />
<strong>Physical Requirements:<br />
</strong>Physical requirements include arm and hand dexterity
enough to use a keyboard and telephone; occasional lifting and
carrying up to 50 pounds; occasional pushing up to 60 pounds; may
be subject to walking, standing, sitting, reaching, balancing,
bending, kneeling, crawling, handling, climbing, and smelling; and
vision, speech, and hearing sufficient to perform the essential
tasks.<br />
<br />
<strong>Licenses and Certificates:<br />
</strong>Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's
License; possession of a Certified Technician certificate by the
Institute for Certification of Engineering Technicians and/or
Surveyor in Training certificate by State of Oklahoma and some
positions will require registration as a Professional Land Surveyor
by the State of Oklahoma. <strong><br />
<br />
Skills Test Required:<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position. A written assessment will
be administered.<br />
<br />
<strong>Working Environment:<br />
</strong>Working environment is primarily indoors in an office
setting and occasionally outdoors and in inclement weather; may be
exposed to traffic, confined spaces, temperature/weather extremes
and climbing hazards; and requires travel to various City locations
and shift changes for assigned duties.<br />
<br />
</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>IT Project Manager</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/it-project-manager.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/it-project-manager.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under direction is responsible for implementing, managing, coordinating and ensuring successful and timely completion of projects for multiple departments and performs other related assigned duties.
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 2213-0002SN<br />
Information Technology, Administration and Planning<br />
Pay Grade: IS-44 / Salary Range: negotionable&nbsp;</p>

<p><span><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong></span>Performs project management duties, including
planning, prioritizing, coordinating, and controlling the analysis,
design, implementation, documentation, testing and maintenance
phases, if applicable, for both IT and non-IT projects<br />
<br />
Determines and assigns/delegates and deploys personnel and
technical resources required to successfully complete projects on
schedule and within budget, ensuring project objectives
fulfilled<br />
<br />
Provides guidance and assistance to project personnel and mentoring
on project management methodology<br />
<br />
Monitors system changes, analyzing impact on business requirements
and revising as required<br />
<br />
Employs project planning and control for the development and
maintenance of project schedules<br />
<br />
Maintains on-going communication with users throughout the life of
projects<br />
<br />
Assesses projects risk on a regular basis, taking appropriate
action to ensure project objectives timely and successfully
met<br />
<br />
Maintains and provides regular comprehensive status reports and
project schedules<br />
<br />
Conducts training needs analysis, interviewing and surveying to aid
in planning training programs, meet business needs and assist in
developing, implementing and providing training materials<br />
<br />
Prepares proposals for new projects<br />
<br />
Develops RFP's/specifications for new systems/modules and evaluates
vendor responses<br />
<br />
Leads and/or attends various meetings to communicate information,
develop IT partnership relationship, advise, recommend and make
presentations created to present technical
proposals/plans/documentation<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</span></strong>Graduation from an accredited college or university
with a bachelor's degree in computer science, management
information science or a related field; and five (5) years
experience working in a professional environment as a project
facilitator, coordinator or leader; or an equivalent combination of
training and experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures,
Section 128.</p>

<p>Comprehensive knowledge of systems analysis and design methods
and techniques; considerable knowledge of designing, documenting
and implementing business solutions; and good knowledge of project
management methodology.&nbsp; Ability to effectively employ
concepts and techniques of project management, including planning,
control and deployment of resources; ability to manage tasks,
resources, vendors and assess risks; ability to analyze complex
concepts/ideas; ability to plan training programs; ability to work,
mentor and provide guidance/training to all levels of personnel;
ability to effectively communicate both verbally and in writing,
creating and making public presentations; ability to work
independently and as a team; ability to understand project
management methodology and take responsibility for successful
management and completion of projects; ability to work on
fast-paced, multiple projects of varying complexity with tight
deadlines, continually adapting to changing priorities; and the
ability to understand and influence the behavior of others within
the organization, customers or the public in order to achieve job
objectives and cause action or understanding.</p>

<p><strong><span>Physical Requirements:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</span></strong> Physical requirements include arm and hand
steadiness and finger dexterity enough to use a keyboard and
telephone; occasional lifting and carrying up to 20 pounds; may be
subject to walking, standing, sitting, reaching, bending, kneeling
and handling; and vision, speech and hearing sufficient to perform
the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Licenses and Certification:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</span></strong> Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operators
License.</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</span></strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
<strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily indoors in an
office setting and may require some travel to various City
locations to review systems.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Pretreatment Manager </title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/pretreatment-manager-.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/pretreatment-manager-.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general direction is responsible for advanced engineering and administrative work in planning, coordinating, and managing an environmental monitoring group involved in industrial/commercial wastewater quality and hazardous materials, ensuring the City's compliance with all applicable federal, state and local environmental regulations and performs other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 4721-0001 RKV<br />
Water and Sewer, Water Quality Assurance<br />
Pay Grade: EX-40 / Salary Range: $1,722 - $3,290/bi-weekly.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:</strong><br />
Interprets and assures compliance with ordinances, state and
federal regulations and the City's OPDES (Oklahoma Pollutant
Discharge Elimination System) Permit, pertaining to sanitary sewer
disposal of industrial/commercial waste<br />
<br />
Supervises the work of subordinates engaged in processing
applications for permits to discharge into the City's sanitary
sewer system<br />
<br />
Manages handling of hazardous materials and wastes<br />
<br />
Manages subordinates engaged in sampling wastewater, streams and
rivers<br />
<br />
Manages subordinates/contractors engaged in environmental audits
and /or assessments<br />
<br />
Controls the establishment and adjustment of sewer service
discharges for industrial users and other special accounts<br />
<br />
Directs compliance monitoring of industrial/commercial discharges
and the collection and accounting of permit fees, monitoring chares
and fines<br />
<br />
Reviews and approves plans for pretreatment technologies submitted
by prospective discharges<br />
<br />
Interprets and assures industry compliance with federal regulations
and EPA permits through an approved enforcement program<br />
<br />
Cooperates with federal and state agencies and other City
departments regarding environmental concerns<br />
<br />
Promotes voluntary compliance by commercial/industrial entities
concerning pollutant and hazardous discharges to the sanitary sewer
system<br />
<br />
Administers the pretreatment and related environmental
programs<br />
<br />
Directs and trains personnel and enforces compliance with
applicable federal, state and local pretreatment regulations<br />
<br />
Administers performance appraisals and makes recommendations on
hiring, disciplinary and termination actions<br />
<br />
Manages projects as requested<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:</strong><br />
Graduation from an accredited college or university with a
bachelor's degree in environmental engineering, chemistry or other
science related fields; and four (4) years of experience related to
industrial pretreatment, wastewater treatment and industrial waste
disposal with at least 2 years of supervisory experience in a
regulatory or laboratory environment; or an equivalent combination
of training and experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures,
Section 128.</p>

<p>Considerable knowledge of federal, state and local laws, codes
and regulations, pertaining to waste disposal and clean water
standards; considerable knowledge of the principles, techniques and
processes of wastewater treatment and pretreatment technologies;
ability to plan and supervise the work of others; ability to
prepare comprehensive reports and maintain detailed records; and
the ability to utilize the highest level of interpersonal skill in
order to understand, select, develop and motivate people at any
level within or outside the organization.</p>

<p><strong>Physical
Requirements:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Physical requirements include arm and hand dexterity enough to use
a keyboard and telephone; frequent lifting and carrying up to 60
pounds; may be subject to walking, standing, sitting, reaching,
balancing, bending, kneeling, handling, climbing, smelling and
twisting; and vision, speech and hearing sufficient to perform the
essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and
Certificates:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License and
possession of a "B" Wastewater Operator and Lab Licenses as issued
by the Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) or ability to
obtain within the time allotted by law; and certification of OSHA
40 hour Hazardous Material Response Training.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Tests Required:</strong><br />
Word, Excel and Access along with a written assessment will be
administered for this position.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:</strong><br />
Working environment is primarily indoors in an office setting; and
occasionally outdoors and in inclement weather; and requires some
travel to various locations to conduct inspections.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Tulsa Parking Authority Administrator</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/tulsa-parking-authority-administrator.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/tulsa-parking-authority-administrator.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general direction manages the representation of the authority in general contract management and the direction and administration of construction/demolition, architectural and engineering services, maintenance/security agreements related to public improvement, commercial building, demolition projects and parking facilities and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code:&nbsp; 7646-0001RKV<br />
Planning &amp; Economic Development, Economic Development<br />
Pay Grade:&nbsp; EX-44 / Salary Range:&nbsp; $1,902 -
$3,635/bi-weekly.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>Manages and directs the work of the support and contract
staffs<br />
<br />
Directs and coordinates activities of outside professional
firms<br />
<br />
Develops, administers, monitors and evaluates professional services
agreements<br />
<br />
Oversees the preparation and administration of contract documents
to ensure standards within state, federal and City guidelines for
multiple funding's coverage<br />
<br />
Establishes contract timeframes and negotiates contractor's
fees<br />
<br />
Develops, maintains and improves procedures for monitoring contract
requirements<br />
<br />
Reviews correspondence, reports and resolutions on behalf of Tulsa
Parking Authority (TPA)<br />
<br />
Assists with the selection of professional services firms on behalf
of TPA and the City<br />
<br />
Reviews environmental audits and monitors compliance with disposal
plans<br />
<br />
Oversees public improvement, commercial building and demolition
projects and coordinates with planning projects<br />
<br />
Prepares, monitors and manages the section's budget and preparation
of renewal/replacement budgets for parking garage facilities<br />
<br />
Analyzes development trends and enables strategic plans to support
infrastructure development<br />
<br />
Facilitates support project development, financial packaging and
cost estimates related to public improvements<br />
<br />
Oversees technical specification development<br />
<br />
Reviews, analyzes and manages progress estimates and parking
authority budgets<br />
<br />
Develops new programs and recommends policy on behalf of authority
and joint city projects<br />
<br />
Plans the ensuing year's workload<br />
<br />
Directs staff presentations<br />
<br />
Oversees contract database development for TPA<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
This position will serve as the Executive Director for the Tulsa
Parking Authority.</p>

<p>Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Qualifications:<br />
</strong>Graduation from an accredited college or university with a
bachelor's degree in business or public administration,
construction management, architectural engineering or related
field, and five (5) years of experience in contract administration,
design or construction management, including four (4) years
experience in budget preparation; or an equivalent combination of
training and experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures,
Section 128.</p>

<p>Comprehensive knowledge of the federal, state and local laws
relating to authority and municipal operations; comprehensive
knowledge of the principles and practices of management and
administration; comprehensive knowledge of contract compliance,
monitoring procedures, building codes and construction techniques;
considerable knowledge of the applications of various computer
software packages and LAN systems; and working knowledge of
authority. Ability to plan, manage and coordinate activities of
both internal and external personnel effectively; ability to assess
various records; ability to clearly and effectively communicate
both verbally and in writing; ability to analyze development trends
and effect strategic infrastructure plans to support new
development; ability to interpret plans, specifications and
blueprints; ability to develop, prepare and manage budgets; ability
to interpret authority policy; and the ability to understand and
influence the behavior of others within the organization, customers
or the public in order to achieve job objectives and cause action
or understanding.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Physical requirements include arm and hand dexterity
enough to use a keyboard and telephone; occasional lifting and
carrying up to 50 pounds; may be subject to walking, standing,
sitting, reaching, balancing, bending and kneeling; and vision,
speech and hearing sufficient to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><br />
<strong>Licenses and Certificates:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Working environment is primarily indoors in an office
setting.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Water Laboratory Technician </title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/water-laboratory-technician-.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/water-laboratory-technician-.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision is responsible for analytical work related to the preparation and testing of water, wastewater, storm water, and environmental samples, and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 3742-0040RKV<br />
Water and Sewer, Water Quality Assurance<br />
Pay Grade: ST-27 / Salary Range: $1,485 - $2,333/bi-weekly.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>Conducts laboratory analysis of basic to moderate
difficulty, involving inorganic, organic, instrumental and
microbial analytical procedures<br />
<br />
Monitors and conducts work to assure all quality control procedures
are in place and complied with<br />
<br />
Monitors inventory of equipment and chemical supplies and alerts
supervisor when replacement is necessary<br />
<br />
Conducts daily analysis in compliance with safe laboratory
practices and complies with the Chemical Hygiene Plan and Hazardous
Communication Policy<br />
<br />
Assures that laboratory equipment is calibrated, cleaned and
maintained in proper working order<br />
<br />
Prepares and maintains chemical analysis records and compiles data
for reports both written and verbal</p>

<p>Properly receives and logs samples into the laboratory and
assures that the samples are properly identified on chain of
custody, properly preserved and distributed within the
laboratory<br />
<br />
Safely disposes of water, wastewater, storm water and other
environmental samples<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis.<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</strong>Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Education Development Certificate (GED) plus 20 accredited college
hours in a related field and one (1) year of laboratory experience;
or an equivalent combination of training and experience per
Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section 128. Refer to the
Laboratory Technician Progression Criterion Document for additional
requirements.</p>

<p>General knowledge of laboratory equipment, terminology, and
standard laboratory techniques and procedures; and knowledge of
standard safety practices and procedures as related to the
laboratory; Ability to perform a variety of analytical analyses
involving inorganic, organic, microbiological, some instrumental
analysis; ability to maintain accurate and legal records; ability
to handle toxic, caustic, and acidic materials; ability to follow
verbal and written instructions; and the ability to courteously and
tactfully communicate with fellow workers, supervisors, other
members of the organization, and the public in giving and receiving
information.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:<br />
</strong>Physical requirements include arm and hand steadiness and
finger dexterity enough to use a keyboard and telephone; occasional
lifting up to 50 pounds; may be subject to extended periods of
standing and walking; reaching, balancing, bending, crawling,
climbing, and smelling; and vision, speech, and hearing sufficient
to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:<br />
</strong>Possession of a valid Class "D" Operator's License.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Test Required<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:<br />
</strong>Working environment is primarily indoors.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Water Supply Systems Manager</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/water-supply-systems-manager.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/professional/water-supply-systems-manager.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under administrative direction is responsible for advanced professional engineering, planning, and administrative work in directing the Flowline Water Supply and the Water Treatment Plants of the Water and Sewer Department. Note: Registration as a PE and DEQ-A water license must be obtained within six (6) months of hire date. 
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 4794-0001SN<br />
Water and Sewer, Water Supply<br />
Pay Grade: EX-52 / Salary: Negotiable/DOE</p>

<p><strong><span>General Purpose:<br />
</span></strong>Exercises overall supervision of City water supply
properties including Lake Spavinaw, Lake Eucha, two terminal
reservoirs and two flowlines<br />
<br />
Exercises general direction over the planning, coordination, and
operation of the water treatment in the Water and Sewer
Department<br />
<br />
Initiates, directs and assists in communication, coordination and
cooperation of work efforts with other City departments,
consultants, contractors and outside agencies to achieve Water and
Sewer Department goals and objectives<br />
<br />
Oversees requisitions and fund disbursement<br />
<br />
Resolves personnel issues<br />
<br />
Reviews design and modification plans for water plants<br />
<br />
Coordinates the preparation of specifications for material and
equipment needs<br />
<br />
Initiates studies to determine adequacy and effectiveness of
current operations<br />
<br />
Recommends and establishes new methods and procedures for improving
efficiency<br />
<br />
Directs the preparation of and administers the annual budget for
Water Supply Systems<br />
<br />
Conducts and attends official meetings and conferences relating to
department operations<br />
<br />
Ensures operations are in compliance with applicable federal, state
and local regulations as well as City and departmental
policies<br />
<br />
Assists and performs work involving the preparation and review of
contracts and proposals<br />
<br />
Prepares, reviews and presents written and verbal reports<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Qualifications:<br />
</span></strong>Graduation from an accredited college or university
with a bachelor's degree in civil, chemical or general engineering
or chemistry, and eight (8) years of progressively responsible
experience in municipal water treatment.</p>

<p>Comprehensive knowledge of municipal water treatment objectives,
purposes, practices and methods; comprehensive knowledge of water
engineering principles as they apply to the maintenance, repair and
operation of a water treatment facility; comprehensive knowledge of
the laws, ordinances and regulations relating to the planning,
development and maintenance of water treatment facilities;
considerable knowledge of modern developments and sources of
information regarding water treatment operations and
engineering.&nbsp; Ability to plan, direct, coordinate and
supervise the work of professional, sub-professional, and technical
personnel engaged in maintenance and operation of water treatment
facilities; ability to prepare comprehensive reports and
recommendations for improved and expanded service; ability to work
effectively with others in complex and controversial situations
with appropriate tact and courtesy; ability to formulate short and
long range plans necessary to accomplish the goals of the
department; ability to express ideas and recommendations
effectively; and the ability to utilize the highest level of
interpersonal skill in order to understand, select, develop, and
motivate people at any level within or outside the
organization.</p>

<p><strong><span>Physical Requirements:<br />
</span></strong>Physical requirements include arm and hand
steadiness and finger dexterity enough to use a keyboard and
telephone; frequent lifting up to 20 pounds with occasional lifting
up to 60 pounds; frequent carrying, pushing and pulling up to 10
pounds with occasional carrying, pushing and pulling up to 60
pounds; may be subject to walking, standing, sitting, reaching,
balancing, bending, kneeling, crawling, handling, feeling,
climbing, smelling and twisting; and vision, speech and hearing
sufficient to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Licenses and Certificates:<br />
</span></strong>Both registration as a professional engineer in the
State of Oklahoma and a Class "A" Water Plant Operator's License as
issued by the Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) must be
obtained within six (6) months of hire date.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</span></strong> Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily indoors in an
office setting and occasionally outdoors and in inclement weather;
and requires some travel to various City locations to oversee
problem corrections.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Computer Support/Lan Senior Technician</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/information-technology/computer-supportlan-senior-technician-.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/information-technology/computer-supportlan-senior-technician-.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision is responsible for planning, technical, analytical and training work supporting end users in the selection and adaptation of micro-computer hardware and software applications, and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 2237-0005RKV<br />
Information Technology, Public Services<br />
Pay Grade:&nbsp; IT-28 / Salary Range: $16.95 - $27.68/Hr.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>Evaluates, studies, plans and recommends software
applications and hardware systems for microcomputer user
needs<br />
<br />
Works with users to troubleshoot and solve problems in hardware
systems or software packages<br />
<br />
Installs, maintains, upgrades and backs up computers and
network<br />
<br />
Programs computers<br />
<br />
Contacts technical support personnel and vendors for purchasing
concerns, technical information, maintenance and repair service
needs<br />
<br />
Writes user procedures, application documentation and sets up data
security systems<br />
<br />
Trains users on personal computers, host terminals and a wide
variety of end user programs<br />
<br />
Writes program revisions or program enhancements, to accomplish
data collection, retrieval, analysis and informational goals<br />
<br />
Performs network administrator tasks, including database backup,
maintenance and related user training<br />
<br />
Provides system reports, statistical reports, requisitions,
purchase orders and other written information<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</strong>Graduation from an accredited college or university with
an associate's degree or sixty (60) college hours in computer
science or other related fields; and two (2) years of microcomputer
system end user support experience; or a bachelor's degree in
computer science or other related fields; or an equivalent
combination of training and experience per Personnel Policies and
Procedures Section 128.&nbsp; Refer to the Computer Support
Progression Criterion Document for additional requirements.</p>

<p>Considerable knowledge of data processing equipment, LANS,
operating systems, and software applications; considerable
knowledge of the methods and techniques used in programming and
troubleshooting micro-computer systems; and good knowledge of host
terminal systems and user training techniques.&nbsp; Ability to
write procedural specifications, program documentation, and train
users; ability to solve system and programming problems; and the
ability to courteously and tactfully communicate with fellow
workers, supervisors, other members of the organization, and the
public in giving and receiving information.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Physical requirements include arm and hand dexterity
enough to use a keyboard and telephone; frequent lifting and
carrying up to 20 pounds with occasional lifting and carrying up to
50 pounds; occasional pushing and pulling up to 60 pounds; may be
subject to walking, standing, sitting, reaching, balancing,
bending, kneeling, crawling, handling, feeling, climbing, and
smelling; vision, speech, and hearing sufficient to perform the
essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's
License.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:<br />
</strong>Working environment is primarily indoors in an office
setting.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>IT Project Manager</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/information-technology/it-project-manager.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/information-technology/it-project-manager.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under direction is responsible for implementing, managing, coordinating and ensuring successful and timely completion of projects for multiple departments and performs other related assigned duties.
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 2213-0002SN<br />
Information Technology, Administration and Planning<br />
Pay Grade: IS-44 / Salary: negotiable</p>

<p><strong><span>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</span></strong>Performs project management duties, including
planning, prioritizing, coordinating, and controlling the analysis,
design, implementation, documentation, testing and maintenance
phases, if applicable, for both IT and non-IT projects<br />
<br />
Determines and assigns/delegates and deploys personnel and
technical resources required to successfully complete projects on
schedule and within budget, ensuring project objectives
fulfilled<br />
<br />
Provides guidance and assistance to project personnel and mentoring
on project management methodology<br />
<br />
Monitors system changes, analyzing impact on business requirements
and revising as required<br />
<br />
Employs project planning and control for the development and
maintenance of project schedules<br />
<br />
Maintains on-going communication with users throughout the life of
projects<br />
<br />
Assesses projects risk on a regular basis, taking appropriate
action to ensure project objectives timely and successfully
met<br />
<br />
Maintains and provides regular comprehensive status reports and
project schedules<br />
<br />
Conducts training needs analysis, interviewing and surveying to aid
in planning training programs, meet business needs and assist in
developing, implementing and providing training materials<br />
<br />
Prepares proposals for new projects<br />
<br />
Develops RFP's/specifications for new systems/modules and evaluates
vendor responses<br />
<br />
Leads and/or attends various meetings to communicate information,
develop IT partnership relationship, advise, recommend and make
presentations created to present technical
proposals/plans/documentation<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</span></strong>Graduation from an accredited college or university
with a bachelor's degree in computer science, management
information science or a related field; and five (5) years
experience working in a professional environment as a project
facilitator, coordinator or leader; or an equivalent combination of
training and experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures,
Section 128.</p>

<p>Comprehensive knowledge of systems analysis and design methods
and techniques; considerable knowledge of designing, documenting
and implementing business solutions; and good knowledge of project
management methodology.&nbsp; Ability to effectively employ
concepts and techniques of project management, including planning,
control and deployment of resources; ability to manage tasks,
resources, vendors and assess risks; ability to analyze complex
concepts/ideas; ability to plan training programs; ability to work,
mentor and provide guidance/training to all levels of personnel;
ability to effectively communicate both verbally and in writing,
creating and making public presentations; ability to work
independently and as a team; ability to understand project
management methodology and take responsibility for successful
management and completion of projects; ability to work on
fast-paced, multiple projects of varying complexity with tight
deadlines, continually adapting to changing priorities; and the
ability to understand and influence the behavior of others within
the organization, customers or the public in order to achieve job
objectives and cause action or understanding.</p>

<p><strong><span>Physical Requirements:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</span></strong> Physical requirements include arm and hand
steadiness and finger dexterity enough to use a keyboard and
telephone; occasional lifting and carrying up to 20 pounds; may be
subject to walking, standing, sitting, reaching, bending, kneeling
and handling; and vision, speech and hearing sufficient to perform
the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Licenses and Certification:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</span></strong> Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operators
License.</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</span></strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
<strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily indoors in an
office setting and may require some travel to various City
locations to review systems.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Systems Section Manager </title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/information-technology/systems-section-manager--(1).aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/information-technology/systems-section-manager--(1).aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under direction is responsible for planning, coordinating and controlling the technical staff and activities related to the production, development, system administration support for information technology systems and projects and performs other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 2273-0006RKV<br />
Information Technology, Server Services<br />
Pay Grade: IS-48 / Salary Range: $2,501 - $4,084/bi-weekly.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>Performs project management duties for assigned user
requested development and maintenance for multi-vendor,
multi-operating information technology applications and projects,
including planning, prioritizing, coordinating, and controlling the
analysis, design, programming, implementation, documentation and
maintenance phases for mainframe, mid, mini and client server
environments<br />
<br />
Determines personnel and technical resources required to
successfully complete projects on schedule and within budget<br />
<br />
Deploys available personnel to production support and projects to
achieve maximum manpower utilization<br />
<br />
Supervises the work of technical subordinates and/or
contractors<br />
<br />
Provides technical training, guidance and assistance to staff<br />
<br />
Performs multi-vendor/operating system technical support for
mainframe, mid, mini, microcomputer and client server systems,
including updates of operating and related system software
products<br />
<br />
Monitors resource utilization, researches alternatives and
recommends appropriate configuration upgrades<br />
<br />
Performs the on-going maintenance of packages application
software<br />
<br />
Employs project planning and control for the development and
maintenance of project schedules<br />
<br />
Maintains on-going communication with users throughout project
development and maintenance<br />
<br />
Develops and enforces section's standards, policies and
procedures<br />
<br />
Develops and monitors technical training<br />
<br />
Responsible for disaster recover procedure development, testing and
implementation for assigned systems<br />
<br />
Assists in the preparation of project schedules and status reports,
the development of divisional objectives and budgets and the
enforcement of operating standards and procedures<br />
<br />
Identifies budget requirements for assigned production systems
and/or proposals<br />
<br />
Develops and presents system configurations and system
proposals<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</strong>Graduation from an accredited college or university with a
bachelor's degree in business administration, computer science,
mathematics or accounting, supplemented by advanced coursework in
computer sciences and six (6) years experience in systems
analysis/design and/or computer programming; or an equivalent
combination of training and experience per Personnel Policies and
Procedures, Section 128.</p>

<p>Comprehensive knowledge of systems analysis and design methods
and techniques; considerable knowledge of programming concepts and
techniques; considerable knowledge of trends in application and
systems software and hardware and mainframe, mid, mini and
microcomputer hardware; and considerable knowledge of accounting,
statistics and modern business principles, methods and practices.
Ability to effectively employ concepts and techniques of project
management, including planning, control and deployment of
resources; ability to supervise a technical staff; ability to
effectively communicate both verbally and in writing; and the
ability to utilize the highest level of interpersonal skill in
order to understand, select, develop and motivate people at any
level within or outside the organization.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Physical requirements include arm and hand steadiness and
finger dexterity enough to use a keyboard and telephone;&nbsp;
lifting and carrying up to 50 pounds; may be subject to walking,
standing, sitting, reaching, bending, kneeling and handling; and
vision, speech and hearing sufficient to perform the essential
tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certification:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</strong> None required.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:<br />
</strong>Working environment is primarily indoors in an office
setting and may require some travel to various City locations to
provide computer related assistance.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Systems Technician II - Service Desk </title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/information-technology/systems-technician-ii---service-desk-.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/information-technology/systems-technician-ii---service-desk-.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision provides routine first-tier technical support to end users with PC, phone, server or mainframe application problems, including activation of computer hardware and software applications and other related assigned duties.
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Codes:&nbsp;2229-0006RKV<br />
Information Technology, Service Desk<br />
Pay Grade: IT-28 / Salary Range: $16.95 - $27.68/Hr.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>Provides technical support to end users via the telephone
or from a remote location, serving as single point of contact
(SPOC) for routine technology-related problems<br />
<br />
Identifies, evaluates, researches and resolves and/or refers
technical computing hardware and software issues, network and other
telecommunications systems issues, documenting, tracking and
monitoring problems to ensure prioritization resolution<br />
<br />
Monitors, identifies and escalates critical problems and system
outages requiring urgent attention<br />
<br />
Sets up end user access to low and medium security hardware systems
and software applications<br />
<br />
Performs routine Service Desk incident management system software
administration duties<br />
<br />
Manages trouble calls and work flows, utilizing monitoring
applications to track and resolve problems with various remote
control tools<br />
<br />
Documents problems, assignments, status and resolutions in Service
Desk incident management system<br />
<br />
Acts as liaison between end users, technical support personnel and
vendors for IT purchasing concerns, technical information,
maintenance and repair service needs until problem resolved<br />
<br />
Researches available hardware and software system documentation to
ensure accurate and appropriate assignment of problems requiring
second and third-tier support<br />
<br />
Provides training, documentation and self-help materials on
personal computers and a wide variety of software applications for
end users<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis</p>

<p>Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</strong>Graduation from an accredited college or university with
an associate's degree in computer science or sixty (60) college
hours towards a degree in computer science or other related fields;
and two (2) years of computer support experience troubleshooting
issues via the phone; or an equivalent combination of training and
experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section 128.
Candidates must have no felony arrests or convictions, nor a
history of multiple misdemeanor arrests/convictions.&nbsp; In
conformance with federal rules and legal mandates, candidates must
undergo a background investigation, including fingerprints.&nbsp;
Should the candidate be selected and accept conditional employment,
failure to pass the background investigation will result in
termination.</p>

<p>Good knowledge of network/computer operating systems; good
knowledge of data communications networking concepts, methods and
techniques, including computer interfacing; good knowledge in
state-of-the-art data processing and communications equipment and
applications; good knowledge of the methods and techniques used in
systems analysis and related maintenance procedures; good knowledge
of data processing systems and equipment; and good knowledge of
PCs, LANs, peripheral equipment and applications.&nbsp; Must
possess the ability to work independently and to recognize,
evaluate and solve system and software maintenance problems;
ability to express and handle oneself in a calm demeanor during
chaotic situations; ability to articulate technical problems in
layman terminology; ability to facilitate Information Technology
training to staff and end users; ability to exercise discretion and
professionalism in handling confidential information; and the
ability to courteously and tactfully communicate with fellow
workers, supervisors, other members of the organization and the
public in giving and receiving information.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Physical requirements include arm and hand dexterity
enough to use a keyboard and telephone; frequent lifting and
carrying up to 50 pounds with occasional pushing and pulling up to
60 pounds; may be subject to walking, standing, sitting, reaching,
bending, kneeling, crawling, handling, climbing and twisting; and
vision, speech and hearing sufficient to perform the essential
tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's
License.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Test Required:<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments will be
administered for each position.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:<br />
</strong>Working environment is primarily indoors in an office
setting.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Engineering Aide II</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/office-support-and-technical/engineering-aide-ii.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/office-support-and-technical/engineering-aide-ii.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision performs subprofessional engineering work in an office or the field, serves as an instrument person on a field survey party, and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 4932-0021SCG<br />
Engineering Services, Field Engineering<br />
Pay Grade:&nbsp; OT-17 / Salary Range: $12.00 - $21.19/Hr.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:</strong><br />
Maintains and operates transits and levels in performing location,
topographic, cross section, and other engineering and land survey
work</p>

<p>Performs layout work for construction of streets, sidewalks,
curbs, water and sewer lines, and other City facilities<br />
<br />
Directs the work of survey crew during absence of the party
chief<br />
<br />
Records elevations, distances, angles, topographic features, and
other data in field book<br />
<br />
Computes grade, elevation, angles, radii, and simple engineering
calculations<br />
<br />
Performs routine design work of water and sewer lines under close
supervision<br />
<br />
Prepares reports<br />
<br />
Maintains and operates a variety of survey instruments and other
equipment<br />
<br />
Operates a City vehicle<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:</strong><br />
Graduation from high school or possession of a General Educational
Development Certificate (GED) with a math background supplemented
by coursework in survey technology or civil engineering, and four
(4) years of experience in general surveying practice; or an
equivalent combination of training and experience, per Personnel
Policies and Procedures, Section 128.<br />
<br />
Good knowledge of the principles, practices methods, and techniques
of subprofessional engineering work; good knowledge of the use and
adjustment of surveying instruments such as transit and
level.&nbsp; Ability to make simple technical mathematical
computations; ability to read and work from blueprints and maps;
ability to make accurate notes and sketches; and the ability to
understand and influence the behavior of others within the
organization, customers, or the public in order to achieve job
objectives and cause action or understanding.&nbsp; Skill in the
operation and maintenance of surveying instruments.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Physical requirements include arm and hand steadiness and finger
dexterity enough to use a keyboard and telephone; frequent lifting
up to 20 pounds with occasional lifting up to 60 pounds; frequent
carrying up to 20 pounds with occasional carrying up to 50 pounds;
occasional pushing up to 20 pounds; occasional pulling up to 60
pounds; may be subject to extended periods of walking and standing;
sitting, reaching, balancing, bending, kneeling, crawling,
handling, feeling, climbing, smelling, and twisting; and vision,
speech, and hearing sufficient to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</strong>Assessments and / or a written assessment will be
administered for this position.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:<br />
</strong>Working environment is primarily outdoors and in inclement
weather and occasionally indoors.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Environmental Monitoring Technician - Progression</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/office-support-and-technical/environmental-monitoring-technician---progression.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/office-support-and-technical/environmental-monitoring-technician---progression.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under direct supervision performs technical, sub professional engineering work in support of environmental programs involved in industrial/commercial waste and storm water quality, stream and potable water distribution system and hazardous material monitoring to ensure compliance with all environmental regulations and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Codes: 4940-0002RKV<br />
Department of Water and Sewer, Water Quality Assurance</p>

<p><strong>This position is part of a progression which means that
we will fill the vacant position commensurate with the selected
candidate's education and experience.&nbsp; Refer to the
Environmental Monitoring Technician Progression Criterion Document
for additional requirements.</strong></p>

<p><strong>EMT I - Pay Grade: OT-17 / Salary Range:&nbsp; $12.00 -
$$21.19<br />
</strong><strong>EMT II - Pay Grade:&nbsp; OT-18 / Salary
Range:&nbsp; $13.53 - $23.90</strong></p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>Sets up, collects, preserves, transports and documents
drinking, surface, waste and storm water samples to ensure sample
collection procedures comply with approved quality assurance and
control techniques<br />
<br />
Installs, operates, sets up, secures, calibrates and maintains
sampling, testing, detecting and monitoring equipment, tools and
devices, including remote automated sampling and flow monitoring
equipment, ph and flow meter, gas detectors and flurimeters<br />
<br />
Operates and maintains computerized database information and
electronic/hard copy files to query, generate, track and document
pertinent sampling information according to prescribed
procedures<br />
<br />
May assist in complaint-based investigations of hazardous materials
spills<br />
<br />
Creates and schedules sampling and monitoring projects and
routes<br />
<br />
Follows chain of custody and other established procedures to allow
use of data acquired for billing purposes and/or as evidence in a
court of law<br />
<br />
Writes informational reports, memos, correspondence and other
documents<br />
<br />
Testifies in a court of law as an expert witness<br />
<br />
Performs technical calculations and field tests utilizing
specialized analytical equipment<br />
<br />
Assists in providing leadership, training, guidance and technical
support to others<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:</strong></p>

<p><strong><span>EMT I</span></strong> <span>-</span>&nbsp;
Graduation from high school or possession of a General Educational
Development Certificate (GED), completion of nine (9) credit hours
from an accredited college in math, science and/or computers and
one (1) year of experience as an Environmental Engineering Aide I
for the City of Tulsa or similar experience.&nbsp; Refer to the
Environmental Monitoring Technician progression criterion document
for additional requirements.</p>

<p>Considerable knowledge of the principles and practices of
environmental engineering, chemistry, hydraulics and related
environmental rules and regulations; considerable knowledge of the
principles and practices of multiple environmental collection,
treatment and distributions systems; and good knowledge of various
computer software applications; and some knowledge of sampling and
laboratory analysis techniques.&nbsp; Ability to read and interpret
engineering atlas plans, maps and specifications; ability to
perform routine laboratory analysis and testing procedures; ability
to keep accurate records and statistical data and perform accurate
calculations; and the ability to understand and influence the
behavior of others within the organization, customers or the public
in order to achieve job objectives and cause action or
understanding.&nbsp; Skill in performing mathematical
computation.</p>

<p><strong>EMT II</strong> - Graduation from high school or
possession of a General Educational Development Certificate (GED),
completion of twenty (20) hours of college accredited coursework to
include math, science and/or computers and one (1) year of
experience as an Environmental Monitoring Technician I for the City
of Tulsa or similar experience. &nbsp;Refer to the Environmental
Monitoring Technician progression criterion document for additional
requirements.</p>

<p>Comprehensive knowledge of the principles and practices of
environmental engineering, chemistry, hydraulics and related
environmental rules and regulations; considerable knowledge of the
principles and practices of multiple environmental collection,
treatment and distributions systems; and considerable knowledge of
various computer software applications; and good knowledge of
sampling and laboratory analysis techniques.&nbsp; Ability to
conduct tests utilizing specialized equipment; ability to keep
accurate records and statistical data and perform accurate
calculations; ability to read and interpret engineering atlas
plans, maps and specifications; and the ability to understand and
influence the behavior of others within the organization, customers
or the public in order to achieve job objectives and cause action
or understanding.&nbsp; Applicant must possess skill in performing
mathematical computations.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Physical requirements include arm and hand steadiness and finger
dexterity enough to use a keyboard and telephone; frequent lifting
up to 50 pounds; frequent carrying up to 30 pounds with occasional
carrying up to 60 pounds; occasional pushing and pulling up to 60
pounds; may be subject to walking, standing, balancing, bending,
kneeling, crawling, handling, feeling, climbing, smelling and
twisting; and vision, speech and hearing sufficient to perform the
essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
<strong>EMT I</strong> -Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D"
Operator's License and the ability to obtain a Class C
Water/Wastewater Laboratory Operators License as issued by the
Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) within one (1) year of
hire date.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong><span>EMT II:</span></strong>&nbsp;&nbsp; Possession of
a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License; and obtain a Class
"C" Water and/or Wastewater Laboratory Operators license as issued
by the Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) within time
allotted by law; and an OSHA 40 hour Hazardous Waste Operator's
Certification.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments&nbsp;will be
administered as needed for each position.&nbsp;&nbsp;The results
will be used in the overall evaluation process.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:</strong><br />
Working environment is primarily outdoors and in inclement weather
and occasionally indoors with exposure to machinery, potentially
hazardous fumes and chemicals, slippery surfaces and confined
spaces; requires traveling to various locations to collect and
deliver samples and may be subject to call-back.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Field Customer Service Representative</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/office-support-and-technical/field-customer-service-representative.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/office-support-and-technical/field-customer-service-representative.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision is responsible for field investigation of water or sewer services to include research, monitoring and resolution of issues related to public utility billing and services for industrial, commercial or residential customers, provides customer service and ensures resolution and recovery of lost water revenues and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 2953-0006SSG<br />
Water &amp; Sewer, Water Distribution / Water Services<br />
Pay Grade: OT-17 / Salary Range: $12.00-$21.19/Hr.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>Reads, monitors and tracks industrial, commercial, and
residential water meter repairs<br />
<br />
Investigates and resolves customer complaints of field activities
related to water services/consumption/billing errors<br />
<br />
Acts as liaison with the public performing advanced level customer
service with both internal and external customers<br />
<br />
Researches and resolves ownership issues related to water
services<br />
<br />
Enforces City of Tulsa codes related to water services issues<br />
<br />
Resolves lost revenue issues involving buried/faulty meters or
unmetered services<br />
<br />
Prepares and maintains records and reports<br />
<br />
Recommends account adjustments due to over-reads, under-reads or
underground leaks and confers with the public and City of Tulsa
staff regarding results of inspections<br />
<br />
Tests meters in the field for accuracy<br />
<br />
Disconnects illegal services<br />
<br />
May act as lead or supervisor as directed<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Qualifications:</strong><br />
Graduation from a two (2) year technical school with coursework in
a related field or thirty (30) college accredited hours and two (2)
years of experience involving public contact, water meter reading,
field utilities inspections, water meter repair, water service
connections, customer services, and/or sewer field operations; or
an equivalent combination of training and experience, per Personnel
Policies and Procedures, Section 128.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Good knowledge of the geography and street locations of the
city, good knowledge of laws, ordinances, regulations and policies
governing city utilities; good knowledge of sanitary and storm
sewer system; and good knowledge of water service locations.&nbsp;
Ability to identify water meter, sanitary or storm sewer defects
and initiate appropriate corrective actions; ability to communicate
effectively both verbally and in writing; and the ability to
understand and influence the behavior of others within the
organization, customers, or the public in order to achieve job
objectives and cause action or understanding.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:<br />
</strong>Physical requirements include arm and hand steadiness and
finger dexterity enough to use a telephone and two-way radio;
occasional lifting and pulling up to 60 pounds; occasional carrying
and pushing up to 20 pounds; may be subject to extended periods of
walking; standing, reaching, balancing, bending, kneeling,
handling, climbing and twisting; and vision, speech, and hearing
sufficient to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:</strong><br />
Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License and
possession of a valid Class "D" Water License as issued by the
Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ); some positions within
this classification require a Class "A" Commercial Driver's License
(CDL).</p>

<p><strong>Skills Tests Required:</strong><br />
Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be administered as
needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:</strong><br />
Working environment is primarily outdoors and in inclement weather
and occasionally indoors; and requires traveling to various
locations for inspections and related tasks. <strong>HOURS:&nbsp;
Tuesday - Friday,&nbsp;7:00 a.m. - 5:30 p.m.</strong></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Senior Environmental Monitoring Technician </title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/office-support-and-technical/senior-environmental-monitoring-technician-.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/office-support-and-technical/senior-environmental-monitoring-technician-.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision is responsible for technical, analytical and subprofessional engineering work involving investigations, inspections, reviews, permitting and monitoring of water, wastewater or storm water systems, industrial pre-treatment and sludge marketing facilities or various environmental compliance concerns and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 4954-0009RKV<br />
Department of Water &amp; Sewer, Water Quality Assurance<br />
Pay Grade: OT-19 / Salary Range: $15.34 - $27.09/Hr.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>May schedule and perform environmental monitoring
inspections of industrial facilities, construction sites and field
locations<br />
<br />
May review compliance requirements and operational effectiveness of
industrial pretreatment systems<br />
<br />
Schedules and assigns technical sampling and flow rate
investigations<br />
<br />
May prepare, issue, renew and change wastewater discharge
permits<br />
<br />
Conducts complaint-based investigations of drinking water issues or
hazardous materials spills<br />
<br />
Calculates sewer charges<br />
<br />
May schedule and assign inspections of grease interceptors<br />
<br />
Maintains drinking and surface water quality or groundwater well
monitoring program<br />
<br />
Directs or leads subordinate personnel in field investigations of
drinking water issues, hazardous spills or other operational work
activities<br />
<br />
May review engineering plans for new and existing storm water or
sanitary pretreatment systems<br />
<br />
Reviews sludge processing plans, special projects and
administrative items<br />
<br />
Trains personnel and assists in ensuring compliance with federal,
state and local or public health environmental requirements<br />
<br />
Maintains Right to Know, Hazardous and solid waste management
programs<br />
<br />
May notify and initiate enforcement actions for reporting discharge
violations by industrial users<br />
<br />
Responds to and investigates drinking water quality issues, illicit
discharges or spills of chemicals and hazardous materials<br />
<br />
Prepares, provides and may present reports and maintains
computerized database information<br />
<br />
Acts as liaison or assists other agencies as directed in relation
to department objectives<br />
<br />
Approves invoices for laboratory services<br />
<br />
Performs technical calculations and lab analysis duties as
required<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</strong>Completion of two (2) years of college coursework from an
accredited college or university in environmental science or
engineering including chemistry coursework and mathematics through
trigonometric functions, and three (3) years of subprofessional
engineering experience, or graduation from an accredited college or
university with a bachelor's degree in environmental or chemical
engineering or chemistry with coursework in computer science; or an
equivalent combination of training and experience per Personnel
Policies and Procedures, Section 128.</p>

<p>Considerable knowledge of the principles and practices of
environmental engineering, chemistry and related environmental
rules and regulations; good knowledge of water distribution and
treatment, wastewater collection, wastewater or storm water quality
and solids handling, treatment and disposal; some knowledge of
sampling and laboratory analysis techniques; knowledge of right to
know and hazardous communications programs; and knowledge of
various computer software applications, including databases, word
processing and spreadsheets.&nbsp; Ability to direct or perform
in-depth field investigations or pretreatment system reviews;
ability to meet legal sampling custody requirements and perform
routine laboratory analysis and testing procedures; ability to
perform accurate trigonometric calculations; and the ability to
understand and influence the behavior of others within the
organization, customers, or the public in order to achieve job
objectives and cause action or understanding.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Physical requirements include arm and hand steadiness and finger
dexterity enough to use a keyboard and telephone; frequent lifting
up to 50 pounds; frequent carrying up to 30 pounds with occasional
carrying up to 60 pounds; occasional pushing and pulling up to 60
pounds; may be subject to walking, standing, balancing, bending,
kneeling, crawling, handling, feeling, climbing, smelling and
twisting; and vision, speech and hearing sufficient to perform the
essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License;
possession of or ability to obtain an OSHA 40 hour Hazardous Waste
Operator's Certificate; and some individuals within this
classification will be required to obtain an applicable
Water/Wastewater License as issued by the Department of
Environmental Quality (DEQ).<br />
<strong><br />
Skills Tests Required:<br />
</strong>Word, Excel and Access assessments will be
administered.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:<br />
</strong>Working environment is a combination of indoors outdoors
in inclement weather with exposure to machinery, toxic fumes and
hazardous chemicals and materials; requires traveling to various
locations to perform inspections, investigations and storm water
monitoring and may be subject to call-back.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Crew Leader II-Distribution (2-Positions)</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/crew-leader-ii-(2-positions).aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/crew-leader-ii-(2-positions).aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision acts as a working leadsperson directing a crew performing a variety of unskilled, semiskilled and skilled tasks while working as a member of a crew engaged in a hazardous, heavy construction and/or major repair or maintenance activities involving City services or facilities and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code:&nbsp; 7934-0016SCG &amp;7934-0018SCG
(2-Positions)<br />
Department of Water and Sewer Distribution, Mainline West<br />
Department of Water and Sewer Distribution, Mainline East<br />
Pay Grade: LT-17/ Salary Range: $14.36/Hr.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:&nbsp; (All
Departments/Divisions):</strong><br />
Performs lead work such as planning activities according to
priority, problem solving and decision making<br />
<br />
Participates with other members of a crew performing a variety of
tasks involving maintenance and repair of water or sewer
lines<br />
<br />
Operates, maintains, instructs others and directs the use of
various types of hand and power equipment<br />
<br />
Operates some specialized types of equipment<br />
<br />
Directs and participates in cleanup of the work area and equipment
upon project completion<br />
<br />
Completes and maintains all required paperwork for each project,
identifying required personnel, equipment and materials used<br />
<br />
Develops and maintains worksite safety, assuring proper placement
of traffic warning devices<br />
<br />
Serves as liaison with customers, landowners, vendors and
contractors<br />
<br />
May trim or remove trees on City right-of-way<br />
<br />
<strong>Distribution Systems</strong><br />
Operates equipment such as a jackhammer and saw<br />
<br />
Pressure tests new water mains<br />
<br />
Inspects, installs, repairs and/or relocates fire, blow-off and
flushing hydrants<br />
<br />
Tests, repairs, rebuilds, replaces and/or adjusts valves and
conducts valve surveys according to atlas page<br />
<br />
Installs, maintains, removes and changes out meters<br />
<br />
Operates and maintains secondary pump and rechlorination
stations<br />
<br />
Installs, repairs and replaces service/water line breaks and
leaks<br />
<br />
Monitors and adjusts water quality and pressure flow<br />
<br />
Diagnoses and corrects low water pressure complaints<br />
<br />
Transports and applies chlorine and sulfur dioxide gases<br />
<br />
Takes and analyzes water samples throughout the distribution
system<br />
<br />
Disinfects, cleans and flushes water mains/lines and storage
tanks<br />
<br />
Constructs concrete meter pits and large concrete valve
vaults<br />
<br />
Builds forms, pours concrete and finishes sidewalks and
driveways</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:</strong><br />
Graduation from high school or possession of a General Educational
Development Certificate (GED), and three (3) years of progressively
responsible experience, including semiskilled and skilled work
in<br />
the major repair or heavy construction field or in water
distribution maintenance with some lead work responsibility; or an
equivalent combination of training and experience per Personnel
Policies and Procedures, Section 128.</p>

<p>Considerable knowledge of manual work practices, methods, tools,
materials and equipment of varied semiskilled major repair and
heavy construction work; considerable knowledge of the City
policies and governmental rules and regulations relating to the
hazards and safety precautions of the work; and prefer demonstrated
knowledge in Oklahoma Department of Environmental Quality
regulations and requirements of Department of Transportation in
some positions.&nbsp; Ability to use and instruct others in the use
of hand and mechanical tools and equipment; ability to operate and
instruct others in the operation of automotive and other types of
power equipment; ability to climb 175 foot water storage tanks;
ability to maintain daily records, ability to perform basic math
calculations, ability to read and interpret plans, specifications
and water, sanitary and storm sewer atlases; and the ability to
understand and influence the behavior of others within the
organization, customers or the public in order to achieve job
objectives and cause action or understanding.</p>

<p><strong>Physical
Requirements:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Physical requirements include frequent walking and standing;
frequent lifts/carries up to 60 pounds; frequent pushing up to 50
pounds; occasional lifts/carries up to 105 pounds; occasional
pushing up to 60 pounds; frequent pulling up to 60 pounds; frequent
reaching, balancing, bending, kneeling, handling, climbing,
smelling and twisting; occasional crawling and feeling; and vision,
speech and hearing sufficient to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and
Certificates:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "A" Commercial
Driver's License (CDL) with applicable endorsements; some positions
within this classification may require a valid Class "D"
Water/Wastewater Operator's License as issued by the Department of
Environmental Quality (DEQ); Confined Space Entry Certification;
and some positions may require Certification on Self Contained
Breathing Apparatus (S.C.B.A.).</p>

<p><strong>Skills Tests Required:</strong><br />
Writing and/or skills assessment may be administered.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:</strong><br />
Working environment is primarily outdoors and occasionally indoors
and in inclement weather.&nbsp; May be exposed to the
following:&nbsp; hazardous materials, animal waste/dead animals,
flammable liquids, radiation, traffic, cramped work areas,
excessive dust, weather/temperature extremes, trench excavations,
underground gas/electric/petroleum/fiber optic lines, rough
terrains, cutting/chipping/grinding, hazardous/toxic atmospheres,
sewage, damp/wet surfaces, snow/ice covered surfaces, animal bites,
snake bites, insect bites, poisonous plants, overhead power lines,
toxic fumes/vapors/odors, confined spaces, compressed gases, high
noise areas and refuse/garbage/litter.&nbsp; Some positions may be
required to work overtime and be on 24 hour standby.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title> Entry Level Labor Pool </title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/entry-level-labor-pool.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/entry-level-labor-pool.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Permanent and Temporary-to-Permanent positions available. Water and Sewer, Streets, Meter Shop, Parks, Surface Drainiange and Vegetation. Require high school diploma or GED, valid driver's license and a minimum of one year general labor experience. We do background checks and drug testing.  Most Entry-level Labor positions start at $10.42 per hour. ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Beginning Salary:&nbsp; Most positions start at $10.42 per
hour.</p>

<p><span>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</span>Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Educational Development Certificate (GED).<br />
<br />
Applicants without high school or GED can be considered at a helper
entry level and will remain at the lower level until a GED has been
obtained and the completion of six months city
employment.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
One (1) to two (2) years experience performing manual labor.<br />
<br />
Experience in concrete work, plumbing, construction, building or
ground maintenance, or the maintenance, repair or installation of
utilities is preferred.<br />
<br />
Must have a stable and verifiable work history.<br />
<br />
Must have a valid Oklahoma Driver's License.<br />
<br />
Must be able to obtain a Commercial Driver's License (CDL) Class
"A" within six (6) months of employment, after completing the
city's CDL training.<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Equipment Operator II - Water Distribution (several positions available)</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/equipment-operator-ii-distribution-.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/equipment-operator-ii-distribution-.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision performs skilled operation of heavy motorized equipment on a regularly designated basis and other related assigned duties. Must have Class-A CDL. ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 7452-SN<br />
Water &amp; Sewer, Water Distribution<br />
Pay Grade: LT-16 / Hourly Rate: $13.04<br />
<br />
<strong><span>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</span></strong>Operates various pieces of light to heavy complex
motorized equipment on a regularly designated basis</p>

<p>Checks for proper functioning of the equipment during operation
and makes needed adjustments</p>

<p>Performs preventative maintenance on equipment, including
operation precheck and services equipment with proper fluids and
lubricants</p>

<p>Operates scrapers, backhoes, tractor-trailer rigs, dozers,
loaders, concrete trucks, batwing mowers, interstate mowers, large
rollers, Big A's, grapples, polecat - digger derricks, profiler -
pavement milling machines, boom/crane trucks, tractor tanker rigs,
dry mix mobile concrete plants, hot box - pothole patchers, brown
bears, dry sludge spreaders, paint stripers, graders (motor
patrol), large bucket trucks, asphalt distributors, and chemical
spray trucks</p>

<p>Operates equipment normally assigned to a higher or lower
classification</p>

<p>Acts regularly as a lead person instructing a small crew of
workers in the operation of assigned equipment</p>

<p>Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.<br />
<strong><br />
<span>Minimum Qualifications:</span></strong><span><br />
</span>Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Educational Development Certificate (GED), and four (4) years of
experience in the operation of larger trucks and heavy equipment;
or an equivalent combination of training and experience per
Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section 128.<br />
<br />
Considerable knowledge of the operation and maintenance
requirements of heavy trucks, construction equipment, and
mechanical systems; good knowledge of local traffic laws and
regulations; good knowledge of cutting and reading survey grade
stakes; and good knowledge of the hazards and applicable safety
rules and regulations of equipment operation.&nbsp; Ability to
operate heavy trucks and construction equipment skillfully and
safely; ability to understand and follow verbal instructions and
read and follow written instructions; ability to complete
paperwork; ability to perform heavy manual labor under any type of
weather conditions; and the ability to courteously and tactfully
communicate with fellow workers, supervisors, other members of the
organization, and the public in giving and receiving
information.&nbsp; Skill in operating and servicing heavy
automotive and construction equipment; and skill in operating and
transporting backhoes.<br />
<br />
<strong><span>Physical Requirements:</span></strong><br />
Physical requirements include occasional walking and standing;
frequent lifting and carrying up to 60 pounds; occasionally
lifts/carries up to 105 pounds; pushing, and pulling up to 60
pounds; frequent climbing, stooping, reaching, bending, handling,
and smelling; occasional balancing, kneeling, crawling, feeling,
and twisting; and vision, speech, and hearing sufficient to perform
essential tasks.<br />
<br />
<strong><span>Licenses and Certificates:</span></strong><br />
Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "A" Commercial Driver's
License (CDL) with applicable endorsements; some positions within
this classification may require an appropriate water/wastewater
license as issued by the Department of Environmental Quality
(DEQ).<br />
<br />
<strong><span>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</span></strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position. An operations assessment
on various heavy equipment will be administered.<br />
<br />
<strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily outdoors and in
inclement weather.&nbsp; May be exposed to the
following:&nbsp;&nbsp; hazardous materials, animal waste/dead
animals, flammable liquids, traffic, cramped work areas, excessive
dust, weather/temperature extremes, trench excavations, underground
gas/electric/petroleum lines, rough terrains,
cutting/chipping/grinding, hazardous/toxic atmospheres, sewage,
damp/wet surfaces, snow/ice covered surfaces, animal bites, snake
bites, insect bites, poisonous plants, overhead power lines, toxic
fumes/vapors/odors, confined spaces, compressed gases, high noise
areas, oily surfaces, water environments, refuse/garbage/litter;
and may be subject to shift irregularities, required to work
overtime and be on 24 hour standby.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Equipment Operator II-Water Dist (Nights)</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/equipment-operator-ii-water-dist-(nights).aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/equipment-operator-ii-water-dist-(nights).aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision performs skilled operation of heavy motorized equipment on a regularly designated basis and other related assigned duties. Shift: 4:00 PM-1:00 AM. 
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 7452-0080SN<br />
Water and Sewer, Water Distribution, Mainline West (Nights)<br />
Pay Grade: LT-16 / Salary Range: $13.04-$18.20/Hr.</p>

<p><strong><span>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</span></strong>Operates various pieces of light to heavy complex
motorized equipment on a regularly designated basis<br />
<br />
Checks for proper functioning of the equipment during operation and
makes needed adjustments<br />
<br />
Performs preventative maintenance on equipment, including operation
precheck and services equipment with proper fluids and
lubricants<br />
<br />
Operates scrapers, backhoes, tractor-trailer rigs, dozers, loaders,
concrete trucks, batwing mowers, interstate mowers, large rollers,
Big A's, grapples, polecat - digger derricks, profiler - pavement
milling machines, boom/crane trucks, tractor tanker rigs, dry mix
mobile concrete plants, hot box - pothole patchers, brown bears,
dry sludge spreaders, paint stripers, graders (motor patrol), large
bucket trucks, asphalt distributors, and chemical spray
trucks<br />
<br />
Operates equipment normally assigned to a higher or lower
classification<br />
<br />
Acts regularly as a lead person instructing a small crew of workers
in the operation of assigned equipment<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Qualifications:<br />
</span></strong>Graduation from high school or possession of a
General Educational Development Certificate (GED), and four (4)
years of experience in the operation of larger trucks and heavy
equipment; or an equivalent combination of training and experience
per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section 128. Successfully
complete the Heavy Equipment Operator Phase I, II and III classes
offered by the City of Tulsa Safety/Training section.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Considerable knowledge of the operation and maintenance
requirements of heavy trucks, construction equipment, and
mechanical systems; good knowledge of local traffic laws and
regulations; good knowledge of cutting and reading survey grade
stakes; and good knowledge of the hazards and applicable safety
rules and regulations of equipment operation.&nbsp; Ability to
operate heavy trucks and construction equipment skillfully and
safely; ability to understand and follow verbal instructions and
read and follow written instructions; ability to complete
paperwork; ability to perform heavy manual labor under any type of
weather conditions; and the ability to courteously and tactfully
communicate with fellow workers, supervisors, other members of the
organization, and the public in giving and receiving
information.&nbsp; Skill in operating and servicing heavy
automotive and construction equipment; and skill in operating and
transporting backhoes.</p>

<p><strong><span>Physical Requirements:<br />
</span></strong>Physical requirements include occasional walking
and standing; frequent lifting and carrying up to 60 pounds;
occasionally lifts/carries up to 105 pounds; pushing, and pulling
up to 60 pounds; frequent climbing, stooping, reaching, bending,
handling, and smelling; occasional balancing, kneeling, crawling,
feeling, and twisting; and vision, speech, and hearing sufficient
to perform essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Licenses and Certificates:<br />
</span></strong>Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "A" Commercial
Driver's License (CDL) with applicable endorsements; some positions
within this classification may require an appropriate
water/wastewater license as issued by the Department of
Environmental Quality (DEQ).</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</span></strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.&nbsp; An equipment
operations assessment will be administered.</p>

<p><strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily outdoors and in
inclement weather.&nbsp; May be exposed to the
following:&nbsp;&nbsp; hazardous materials, animal waste/dead
animals, flammable liquids, traffic, cramped work areas, excessive
dust, weather/temperature extremes, trench excavations, underground
gas/electric/petroleum lines, rough terrains,
cutting/chipping/grinding, hazardous/toxic atmospheres, sewage,
damp/wet surfaces, snow/ice covered surfaces, animal bites, snake
bites, insect bites, poisonous plants, overhead power lines, toxic
fumes/vapors/odors, confined spaces, compressed gases, high noise
areas, oily surfaces, water environments, refuse/garbage/litter;
and may be subject to shift irregularities, required to work
overtime and be on 24 hour standby. Core Hours: Nights, Monday-
Friday 4:30PM-1:00AM.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mechanic II</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/mechanic-ii.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/mechanic-ii.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision performs skilled maintenance and repair on a variety of automotive and related equipment, and other related assigned duties.
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 7382-0032SCG<br />
Equipment Management, Fleet Maintenance,<br />
470 W 23rd Street<br />
Pay Grade: LT-18 / Salary: $16.01/Hr.</p>

<p><strong><span>Essential Job Functions:</span></strong><br />
Inspects automobiles, motorcycles, and trucks to locate and
determine the extent of needed repairs and safety condition<br />
<br />
Performs overhaul and repair work on gasoline and diesel engines,
transmissions and drive trains, heating and cooling systems,
alignments, clutches, air brake systems, differentials, exhaust
systems, ignition systems, injection and standard fuel
systems<br />
<br />
Performs tune ups<br />
<br />
Performs extensive hydraulic problem inspections and repairs<br />
<br />
Performs scheduled maintenance and repairs of automotive
equipment<br />
<br />
Operates test equipment<br />
<br />
Makes time and cost material estimates<br />
<br />
Orders parts, supplies, and equipment and maintains stock<br />
<br />
Operates and repairs a variety of light to heavy automotive
vehicles and equipment<br />
<br />
Operates wrecker and performs recovery of wrecked vehicles<br />
<br />
Completes necessary paperwork<br />
<br />
Attends shop safety and training sessions<br />
<br />
May direct the work of Automotive Mechanics I or II, and Automotive
Servicer positions as a working lead person<br />
<br />
Maintains facility, shop equipment, and work area<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</span></strong>Graduation from high school or possession of a
General Educational Development Certificate (GED), and five (5)
years of experience in automotive repair to include at least one
(1) year at the journeyman level; or an associates degree in auto
or diesel mechanics, and three (3) years of experience in
automotive repair to include at least one (1) year at the
journeyman level; or an equivalent combination of training and
experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section 128.</p>

<p>Good knowledge of modern methods, tools, and equipment of the
automotive mechanical trade; good knowledge of the operating
principles and mechanics of internal combustion engines; good
knowledge of heavy automotive equipment; good working knowledge of
motorcycle maintenance and performance handling; good working
knowledge of pneumatic/hydraulic equipment systems; good knowledge
of diesel engines; good knowledge of small engines, and water and
trash pumps; and good knowledge of the occupational hazards and
safety precautions of the trade.&nbsp; Ability to perform heavy
manual labor in rather inaccessible spaces; ability to climb
ladders or platforms at high altitudes; ability to operate heavy
duty automotive equipment; ability to maintain simple time and
material records; and the ability to courteously and tactfully
communicate with fellow workers, supervisors, other members of the
organization, and the public in giving and receiving
information.&nbsp; Skill in the care and use of hand tools and
automotive and related mechanical equipment used in the automotive
mechanical trade; and skill in locating and repairing mechanical
and electrical defects in automotive equipment.</p>

<p><strong><span>Physical Requirements:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</span></strong> Physical requirements include standing and
walking; frequent lifting, carrying, pushing, and pulling up to 50
pounds, occasional lifting, carrying, pushing, and pulling up to 60
pounds; frequent balancing, kneeling, bending, reaching, handling,
feeling, smelling, and twisting; occasional crawling, and climbing;
and vision, speech, and hearing sufficient to perform essential
tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Licenses and
Certificates:</span></strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Some positions within this classification will be required to
obtain a valid Class "A" or "B" Commercial Driver's License (CDL)
within 90 days of the date of hire; and/or a State Inspector's
License; some positions within this classification may be required
to possess an Air Conditioning Repair License; and some positions
within this classification may be required to obtain a Freon
Recovery Certificate within six (6) months of date of hire. *ASE
Certification preferred.</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Assessments Required:</span></strong><br />
Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be administered as
needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily indoors and
occasionally outdoors, and in inclement weather.&nbsp; May be
exposed to the following:&nbsp; hazardous materials, flammable
liquids, traffic, cramped work areas, excessive dust,
weather/temperature extremes, cutting/chipping/grinding, damp/wet
surfaces, snow/ice covered surfaces, toxic fumes/vapors/odors,
compressed gases, high noise areas, extreme heights and required to
be on 24-hour standby. CORE HOURS: M-F 7:00-3:30.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>PAC Lead Maintenance Mechanic</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/pac-lead-maintenance-mechanic-.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/pac-lead-maintenance-mechanic-.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision acts as a working lead in performing skilled/semiskilled maintenance, installation and repair of electrical, mechanical and related maintenance of electronic, plumbing and HVAC systems, event set ups as applicable and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 7367-0001SCG<br />
Performing Arts Center<br />
Pay Grade: LT-17 / Salary Range: $14.36 - $17.47/Hr.</p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions<br />
</strong>Performs as a working lead, participating with a group of
workers involved in a wide variety of planned and scheduled
maintenance and renovation activities<br />
<br />
Leads and participates in setting up and tearing down for various
meeting and performing events<br />
<br />
Operates and maintains plumbing, low pressure steam heating
equipment and chilled water HVAC control system, inspects and
determines maintenance needs regarding the repair or adjustment of
mechanical and related control systems<br />
<br />
Leads in the maintenance and monitoring of fluid transfer, sewer
pump and fire alarm/control systems<br />
<br />
Repairs valves, switches, circuitry, switchboards, gears, starters
and controllers<br />
<br />
Effects electrical, plumbing, pipe fitting, irrigation system and
stationary mechanical maintenance and repairs at a skilled
level<br />
<br />
Operates, repairs and maintains facility emergency generator and
electrical distribution system<br />
<br />
Replaces and/or repairs worn or broken parts, reassembles
components and installs new and rebuilt units, estimating labor,
materials and equipment as required<br />
<br />
Responsible for notifying appropriate personnel of conditions which
may warrant theater evacuation<br />
<br />
Directs movement of work materials and equipment, cleanup of work
areas/equipment upon job completion and monitors, maintains and
orders materials/equipment<br />
<br />
Directs workers in semiskilled carpentry, plumbing, electrical,
grounds upkeep and janitorial service<br />
<br />
May act as senior as requested<br />
<br />
Must report to work on a regular and timely basis<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Qualifications:<br />
</strong>Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Educational Development Certificate (GED), and four (4) years of
progressively responsible skilled mechanical maintenance work,
including three (3) years of experience in the repair, maintenance
and operation of electrical motors, controls and complex mechanical
and related electronic equipment, including experience in general
maintenance and the renovation field with lead work
responsibility;&nbsp; or an equivalent combination of training and
experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section
128.&nbsp; Refer to the Mechanical Utility Worker progression
criterion document for additional requirements.</p>

<p>Considerable knowledge of manual labor work practices; good
knowledge of electrical motors and controls, proper methods of
repair and maintenance, including materials handling systems; good
knowledge of operating principles of pumps and other equipment
related to pressure systems and treatment facilities; good
knowledge of the safety requirements of mechanical maintenance; and
some knowledge of computers to operate motors/pumps and control
systems.&nbsp; Ability to make inspections and diagnose operating
conditions and needed repairs of mechanical, plumbing and related
electronic equipment to ensure expedient repairs; ability to
estimate labor and materials required for repair, maintenance and
servicing of plumbing, electrical and mechanical units and related
equipment; ability to write new equipment specifications; ability
to write routine reports, order and maintain parts, tools and
supply inventories; ability to lead employees in skilled and
semiskilled maintenance activities; and the ability to courteously
and tactfully communicate with fellow workers, supervisors, other
members of the organization and the public in giving and receiving
information.&nbsp; Skill in widely varied electrical and mechanical
installation, repair and maintenance.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:<br />
</strong>Physical requirements include frequent walking and
standing; frequent lifts/carries up to 20 pounds with occasional
lifting up to 80 pounds; occasionally carries/lifts up to 80
pounds; constantly lifts/carries up to 10 pounds; occasional
pulling up to 10 pounds; frequent balancing, kneeling, bending,
handling, feeling, climbing, smelling and twisting; occasional
crawling and reaching; and vision, speech and hearing sufficient to
perform essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:<br />
</strong>Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's
License; and preferably a 3rd Class Stationary Engineer Certificate
or mechanical, electrical or plumbing apprentice license.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Assessments Required:<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong>Working Environment:<br />
</strong>Working environment is primarily indoors and occasionally
outdoors and in inclement weather; and may be exposed to the
following:&nbsp; hazardous materials, flammable liquids, damp/wet
and snow/ice covered surfaces and toxic fumes/vapors/odors.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Plant Mechanic Helper-Sewer Operations (2 positions open)</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/plant-mechanic-helper.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/plant-mechanic-helper.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision is responsible for performing a variety of unskilled and semiskilled tasks; works as a member of a crew engaged in hazardous and/or major repair activities involving City services or facilities, and other related assigned duties.
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 7424SN<br />
Water and Sewer/Sewer Operations and Maintenance<br />
Pay Grade: LT-15U / Starting Pay Rate: $11.95/Hr.</p>

<p><strong><span>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</span></strong>Performs maintenance and preventive maintenance of
lift stations and related facilities<br />
<br />
Performs non-journeyman semiskilled carpentry, plumbing and
electrical work on lift stations<br />
<br />
Operates computer for control of lift stations, data entry and
retrieval<br />
<br />
Maintains and repairs pneumatic compressors and controls and engine
generators<br />
<br />
Repairs motors, pumps and fences<br />
<br />
Cleans wetwells and baskets<br />
<br />
Troubleshoots lift station problems<br />
<br />
Mows and trims grass<br />
<br />
Cleans work areas and equipment upon project completion<br />
<br />
Maintains worksite safety<br />
<br />
Operates a variety of powered and medium to heavy automotive
equipment<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Qualifications:<br />
</span></strong>Graduation from high school or possession of a
General Educational Development Certificate (GED) and one (1) year
of experience performing heavy manual labor involving the basic
operation of electrical, mechanical or plumbing systems; or an
equivalent combination of training and experience per Personnel
Policies and Procedures, Section 128.</p>

<p>Good knowledge of basic manual labor practices, methods, tools
and materials; and some knowledge of the hazards of the work.&nbsp;
Ability to perform heavy manual labor over an extended period of
time in varying weather conditions; ability to understand verbal
instructions and to read and follow written instructions; ability
to learn and perform more responsible tasks; ability to use hand
and mechanical tools and equipment; and the ability to courteously
and tactfully communicate with fellow workers, supervisors, other
members of the organization and the public in giving and receiving
information.</p>

<p><strong><span>Physical Requirements:<br />
</span></strong>Physical requirements include frequent walking and
standing; frequent lifts/carries up to 30 pounds; occasional
lifts/carries up to 68 pounds; constantly lifts/carries up to 10
pounds; requires pulling a maximum force of 135 pounds peak;
frequent reaching, balancing, bending, kneeling, handling, climbing
and twisting; occasional crawling, feeling and smelling; and
vision, speech and hearing sufficient to perform the essential
tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Licenses and Certificates:<br />
</span></strong>Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's
License; and must obtain a valid Class "A" Commercial Driver's
License (CDL) (some positions require a CDL with "N" endorsement)
within ninety (90) days of hire; and must obtain a valid Class "D"
Water/Wastewater License as issued by the Department of
Environmental Quality (DEQ) within six months of hire.</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</span></strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily outdoors and
occasionally indoors, and in inclement weather.&nbsp; May be
exposed to the following: flammable liquids, traffic, cramped work
areas, excessive dust, weather/extreme temperatures, rough terrain,
cutting/chipping/grinding, hazardous/toxic materials, sewage,
damp/wet surfaces, snow/ice covered surfaces, poisonous plants,
overhead power lines, toxic fumes/vapors/odors, confined spaces,
compressed gases, high noises, and oily surfaces.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Plant Mechanic-Southside Wastewater Treatment Plant</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/plant-mechanic-southside-wastewater-treatment-plant.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/plant-mechanic-southside-wastewater-treatment-plant.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ The Plant Mechanic positions, Plant Mechanic I, LT-17, PM II, LT-18 and PM III, LT-19 are part of a progression and the vacant position will be filled at the level that best matches the candidate's education, training and experience.  
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code: 7423-0031SN<br />
Water and Sewer, Water Pollution Control, Southside Wastewater
Plant<br />
PM I- Pay Grade: LT-17 / Beginning Salary: $14.36/Hr.<br />
PM II- Pay Grade:&nbsp; LT-18 / Beginning Salary: $16.01/Hr.<br />
PM III- Pay Grade: LT-19 / Beginning Salary: $16.89/Hr.</p>

<p><strong><span>General Purpose:<br />
</span></strong> Under general supervision is responsible for
semiskilled, skilled or highly skilled maintenance work involving
the operation, installation and maintenance of various water or
wastewater treatment plant mechanical systems and related
facilities and other related assigned duties. *Department prefers
hiring at the Plant Mechanic III level.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Qualifications:<br />
</span></strong>Plant Mechanic I - Graduation from high school or
possession of a General Educational Development (GED) Certificate;
and two (2) years of experience in non-journeyman, semiskilled
electrical, mechanical, plumbing or other mechanical maintenance
related repairs; or an equivalent combination of training and
experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section
128.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License;
must obtain a valid Class "A" Commercial Driver's License (CDL)
within ninety (90) days of hire; and must obtain both an applicable
class "D" Water/Wastewater License as issued by the Department of
Environmental Quality (DEQ) and, if appropriate, an Electrical,
Mechanical or Plumbing Apprentice License as issued by the State of
Oklahoma within six (6) months of hire.</p>

<p>Plant Mechanic II - Graduation from high school or possession of
a General Educational Development (GED) Certificate and three (3)
years of experience in non-journeyman, skilled electrical,
mechanical, plumbing or other mechanical maintenance related
repairs; or an equivalent combination of training and experience
per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section 128.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Option 1:<br />
</strong>Completion of twenty (20) accredited college hours in a
related field, OR&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;Completion of 300 hours of instruction in the applicable
trade category that would meet the formal classroom education
requirements for licensing by the Construction Industries Board of
the state of Oklahoma or in another departmentally approved
technical training area, i.e., carpentry</p>

<p><strong>Option 2:<br />
</strong>Possession of a Third Class Operating Engineer's License
if working on low pressure boilers* AND<br />
Completion of 270* hours of instruction in the applicable trade
category that would meet the formal classroom education
requirements for licensing by the Construction Industries Board of
the state of Oklahoma or in another departmentally approved
technical training area, i.e., carpentry, OR<br />
Completion of eighteen (18*) accredited college hours in a related
field;</p>

<p>Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's License;
possession of a valid Class "A" Commercial Driver's License (CDL);
possession of an applicable Class "C" Water/Wastewater License as
issued by the Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ); and, if
actively working on a journeyman license, an Electrical, Mechanical
or Plumbing Apprentice's License as issued by the State of Oklahoma
and either Option 1 or Option 2 below:</p>

<p><strong><span>Plant Mechanic III-<br />
</span></strong> Graduation from high school or possession of a
General Educational Development (GED) Certificate; and four (4)
years of experience in journeyman level, skilled electrical,
mechanical, plumbing or other mechanical maintenance related
repairs; or an equivalent combination of training and experience
per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section 128.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Completion of forty (40) accredited college hours in a related
field OR<br />
Completion of 600 hours of instruction in the applicable trade
category that would meet the formal classroom education
requirements for licensing by the Construction Industries Board of
the state of Oklahoma or 600 hours of instruction in a
departmentally approved technical training area, i.e., electrical,
mechanical or plumbing or a related area OR<br />
Possession of a Plant Maintenance (PM) Mechanical Technologist
Grade III Certification as issued by the California Water
Environment Association (CWEA) Technical Certification Program
(TCP) OR</p>

<p>*Possession of one (1) of the following as issued by the State
of Oklahoma: Unlimited Journeyman Level Mechanical License;
Unlimited Journeyman Level Electrical License; Journeyman Level
Plumbing License</p>

<p>Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "D" Operator's
License;&nbsp; must obtain a valid Class "A" Commercial Driver's
License (CDL) within ninety (90) days of hire; must obtain an
applicable Class "C" Water/Wastewater License as issued by the
Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) within eighteen (18)
months of hire.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong><span>Physical Requirements:<br />
</span></strong>Physical requirements include frequent walking and
standing; frequent lifts/carries up to 30 pounds with occasional
lifts/carries up to 68 pounds; constantly lifts/carries up to 10
pounds; requires pushing/pulling a maximum force of 100 pounds
peak; frequent reaching, balancing, kneeling, bending, handling,
feeling, climbing, smelling and twisting and occasional crawling;
and vision, speech and hearing sufficient to perform essential
tasks.&nbsp; Some positions within this classification may require
sitting, use of magnification and good hand-eye coordination.
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Test Required:<br />
</span></strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily outdoors and
occasionally indoors, and in inclement weather.&nbsp; May be
exposed to the following:&nbsp; hazardous materials, flammable
liquids, confined spaces, cramped work areas, excessive dust,
weather/temperature extremes, trench excavations, underground
gas/electric/petroleum lines, rough terrains,
cutting/chipping/grinding, hazardous/toxic atmospheres, sewage,
damp/wet surfaces, snow/ice covered surfaces, insect bites,
poisonous plants, toxic fumes/vapors/odors, confined spaces,
compressed gases and high noise areas; and may be required to work
overtime and be on 24 hour stand-by. HOURS: Monday - Friday&nbsp;
7:00 am - 3:30 pm.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Treatment Plant Operator-Wastewater</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/treatment-plant-operator-wastewater-.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/treatment-plant-operator-wastewater-.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Great career opportunity!! Under supervision performs technical and semiskilled work in the operation and maintenance of a water or wastewater treatment plant and other related assigned duties.
]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Water and Sewer, Water Pollution Control<br />
Position Code: 7481-7483</p>

<p>The Treatment Plant Operator positions are in a progression. The
positions range from a TPO I (LT-16) to a Treatment Plant Operator
IV (LT-19).&nbsp; Please refer to the Treatment Plant Operator
Progression documentation and detailed job descriptions located on
the City's Intranet Site.</p>

<p>TPO Apprentice: Pay Grade: LT-15 /&nbsp;starting
$11.38/Hr.&nbsp;<br />
TPO I- Pay Grade: LT-16 /&nbsp;starting $13.04/Hr.<br />
TPO II- Pay Grade:&nbsp; LT-17 /&nbsp;starting $14.36/Hr.<br />
TPO III- Pay Grade: LT-18 /&nbsp;starting $16.01/Hr.<br />
TPO IV- Pay Grade: LT-19 /&nbsp;starting $16.89/Hr.</p>

<p><strong><span>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</span></strong>Operation of mechanical, electrical, electronic,
chemical or other process equipment, including pumps, chemical
feeders, valves, compressors, conveyors, clarifiers, control
panels, and computers;<br />
<br />
Operates a variety of automotive and industrial equipment;<br />
<br />
Monitors and operates all plant equipment;<br />
<br />
Collects water or wastewater samples from various plant processes
for testing purposes;<br />
<br />
Maintains the plant through cleaning, painting, sweeping/moping,
mowing, trimming, and refuse removal;<br />
<br />
Loads and unloads hazardous chemicals;<br />
<br />
Logs plant data, readings, and operational records;<br />
<br />
Performs some analytical tests on water or wastewater
samples.<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.<br />
<br />
*All offers are contingent on passing a national background
check.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Qualifications:<br />
</span></strong>TPO Apprentice- Graduation from high school or
possession of a General Education Development Certificate (GED);
some experience operating electrical, mechanical, electronic,
chemical or other process equipment.&nbsp; Refer to the Treatment
Plant Operator Progression Criterion Document for additional
requirements.</p>

<p>TPO I- Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Educational Development Certificate (GED) and six (6) months
experience as a Treatment Plant Apprentice or similar
experience.&nbsp; Refer to the Treatment Plant Operator progression
criterion document for additional requirements.&nbsp; Progression
to a Treatment Plant Operator II is mandatory and required
coursework to progress to the II level must be obtained within 18
months.</p>

<p>TPO II- Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Educational Development Certificate (GED), completion of nine (9)
credit hours from an accredited college in math, science and/or
computers and one (1) year of experience as a Treatment Plant
Operator I for the City of Tulsa or similar experience.&nbsp; Refer
to the Treatment Plant Operator progression criterion document for
additional requirements.</p>

<p>TPO III- Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Educational Development Certificate (GED), completion of twenty
(20) hours of college accredited coursework to include math,
science and/or computers, one (1) year of experience as a Treatment
Plant Operator II for the City of Tulsa or similar
experience.&nbsp; Refer to the Treatment Plant Operator progression
criterion document for additional requirements.</p>

<p>TPO VI- Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Education Development (GED) Certificate, plus completion of forty
(40) hours college accredited coursework to include math, science
and/or computers, one (1) year experience as a Treatment Plant
Oprator III with the city of Tulsa or similar experience.&nbsp;
Refer to the Treatment Plant Operator Progression Criterion
Document for additional requirements.</p>

<p><strong><span>Licenses and
Certificates:</span></strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
TPO Apprentice- Obtain a Class "B" Commercial Driver's License
(CDL) with an "N" endorsement within ninety (90) days of hire date
in the wastewater area only; and a Class "D" Water/Wastewater
License as issued from the Department of Environmental Quality
(DEQ) within six (6) months of hire date in both water and
wastewater areas.</p>

<p>TPO I- Possession of a valid Class "B" Commercial Driver's
License (CDL) with an "N" endorsement within ninety (90) days of
hire date in the wastewater area only; employees will be required
to obtain a valid Class "D" Water/Wastewater License as issued from
the Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) within six (6) months
of hire date; and in addition, the City of Tulsa requires the
employee to obtain a Class"C" Water/Wastewater License as issued
from the Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) within eighteen
(18) months of hire date.</p>

<p>TPO II- Obtain a Class "B" Commercial Driver's License (CDL)
with an "N" endorsement within ninety (90) days of hire date in the
wastewater area only; and possession of a Class "C"
Water/Wastewater License as issued from the Department of
Environmental Quality (DEQ) in both water and wastewater areas.</p>

<p>TPO III- Obtain a Class "B" Commercial Driver's License (CDL)
with an "N" endorsement within ninety (90) days of hire date in the
wastewater area only; and possession of a Class "B"
Water/Wastewater License as issued from the Department of
Environmental Quality (DEQ) in both water and wastewater areas.</p>

<p>TPO IV- Obtain a Class "B" Commercial Driver's License (CDL)
with an "N" endorsement within ninety (90) days of hire date in the
wastewater area only; and possession of a Class "B"
Water/Wastewater License as issued from the Department of
Environmental Quality (DEQ) in both water and wastewater areas.</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Test Required:<br />
</span></strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Hours: Shift work including nights and weekends.
Working environment is primarily outdoors, occasionally indoors,
and in inclement weather.&nbsp; May be exposed to the
following:&nbsp; hazardous materials, high voltage electrical
equipment, heights, flammable liquids, traffic, cramped work areas,
excessive dust, weather/temperature extremes, rough terrains,
cutting/chipping/grinding, hazardous/toxic atmosphere, sewage,
damp/wet surfaces, snow/ice covered surfaces, snake and insect
bites, poisonous plants, overhead power lines, toxic
fumes/vapors/odors, confined spaces, compressed gases, high noises,
oily surfaces, and refuse/garbage/litter.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Utility Service Worker III (5-Positions)</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/utility-service-worker-iii-(5-positions).aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/labor-and-trade/utility-service-worker-iii-(5-positions).aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under general supervision works independently as a one-man, small or larger crew performing technical diagnosis, maintenance, installation and field repairs to residential/light commercial water meters, AMR devices and service lines and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code:&nbsp;&nbsp;7314-0002SCG &amp; 7314-0003SCG
&amp;&nbsp;7314-0006&nbsp;SCG &amp;&nbsp;7314-0008SCG &amp;
7314-0015SCG (5-Positions)<br />
Dept of Water and Sewer, Distribution Maintenance, Meter Shop<br />
Pay Grad: LT-16 / Salary: $13.04/Hr.</p>

<p><strong><span>Essential Job Functions:</span></strong></p>

<p>Diagnoses, tests, installs, removes, replaces and makes field
repairs to small water meters and service lines, ensuring
compliance with Oklahoma Underground Facilities Protection Act and
ODEQ/OSHA regulations</p>

<p>Repairs/replaces service lines, curb stops and meter
setters/cans, ensuring proper service operation</p>

<p>Acts as competent person to eliminate hazards in trenching and
confined space operations, maintaining worksite safety</p>

<p>Troubleshoots, tests, repairs, programs and installs Automated
Meter Reading (AMR) devices</p>

<p>Inspects, diagnoses and corrects/resolves extreme water
bill/leak/low pressure/no water complaints and reports/corrects
meter tampering violations</p>

<p>Assesses situation and determines most cost effective method and
materials needed to resolve problem and meet quotas and
deadlines</p>

<p>Maintains inventory and detailed records, including work orders,
safety permits, credit work and material checkout/paving cut/trench
forms</p>

<p>Performs semiskilled pipefitting, welding, plumbing and masonry
in utility services repair and maintenance activities</p>

<p>Operates and maintains a variety of heavy automotive
equipment</p>

<p>May work as a member of a crew on special projects or as a
working lead multiple one-man crews when required</p>

<p>Cross trains in higher classifications</p>

<p>Must report to work on a regular and timely basis</p>

<p>Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Minimum Qualifications:<br />
</span></strong>Graduation from high school or possession of a
General Educational Development Certificate (GED), and three (3)
years of heavy manual labor experience to include mechanical
equipment repair or plumbing experience; preferably supplemented by
completion of six (6) accredited college hours; including one (1)
year of experience as an Utility Service Worker II; or an
equivalent combination of training and experience per Personnel
Policies and Procedures, Section 128.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Good knowledge of manual work practices, methods, hazards and
materials used in the repair and maintenance of residential and
light commercial water meters; and good knowledge of the hazards
and safety precautions of the work and the water distribution
system.&nbsp; Ability to detect and diagnose defects in water
meters, make repairs/replacement and ensure proper operation;
ability to properly utilize plumbers tools and appropriate repair
materials; ability to work on a small crew or independently and
plan work projects meeting quotas; ability to communicate
effectively and deal with irate customers on a daily basis; ability
to maintain detailed work records, utilizing appropriate computer
applications; ability to perform complex mathematical calculations;
ability to perform tasks under generally unfavorable conditions
such as extreme heat, cold, wetness in a confined space and
extremely awkward positions; and the ability to understand and
influence the behavior of others within the organization, customers
or the public in order to achieve job objectives and cause action
or understanding.&nbsp; Skilled in the use and care of laptop
computer, hand tools and small power equipment.</p>

<p><strong><span>Physical Requirements:<br />
</span></strong>Physical requirements include standing and walking;
frequent lifting up to 60 pounds and occasional lifting up to 80
pounds; frequent carrying up to 60 pounds and occasional carrying
up to 80 pounds; frequent pushing up to 20 pounds and occasional
pushing up to 60 pounds; frequent pulling up to 20 pounds and
occasional pulling up to 60 pounds; frequent balancing, bending,
reaching, kneeling, crawling, handling, climbing, and twisting;
occasional feeling and smelling;&nbsp; and vision, speech, and
hearing sufficient to perform essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong><span>Licenses and Certificates:<br />
</span></strong>Possession of a valid Oklahoma Class "A" Commercial
Driver's License (CDL) with an "N" endorsement within 6 months of
hire date; must obtain a Class "D" Water License from the Oklahoma
Department of Environmental Quality (ODEQ) within 6 months of hire
date; and Confined Space Entry, Trenching and Shoring Certification
as a competent person.</p>

<p><strong><span>Skills Tests Required:<br />
</span></strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p><strong><span>Working Environment:<br />
</span></strong>Working environment is primarily outdoors and
occasionally indoors, and in inclement weather.&nbsp;&nbsp; May be
exposed to the following:&nbsp; hazardous materials, flammable
liquids, traffic, cramped work areas, weather/temperature extremes,
underground gas/electric/petroleum lines, rough terrains,
cutting/chipping/ grinding, damp/wet surfaces, snow/ice covered
surfaces, animal bites, snake bites, insect bites, poisonous
plants, toxic fumes/vapors/odors, confined spaces, high noise
areas, and may be subject to shift changes.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>School Crossing Escort (Part-time) </title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/part-time,-temporary,-summer-jobs-and-internships/school-crossing-escort-(part-time).aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/part-time,-temporary,-summer-jobs-and-internships/school-crossing-escort-(part-time).aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Would you like to perform a vital job responsibility, protect our youth, and earn MONEY?  Would you like to be a child's hero?  A School Crossing Escort may be just the position for you.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p style="text-align: justify;">The successful candidate must LOVE
children, be over twenty-one, possess a telephone, valid Driver's
License &nbsp;and reliable transportation, be in good physical
condition, with no criminal record, and be available on short
notice.&nbsp; Work sites are available throughout the Tulsa
area.&nbsp; The work shifts are three (3) to five (5) hours per day
between the hours of 7:00 a.m. - 4:30 p.m. <strong>Pay:
$7.55/hr.</strong><br />
<br />
If the above description sounds interesting to you, please apply at
City Hall in the One Technology Center, 175 East Second Street,
Suite 280 or fill out an online applicaiton at <a
href="http://www.cityoftulsa.jobs">www.cityoftulsa.jobs</a>.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cashier</title><link>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/part-time,-temporary,-summer-jobs-and-internships/cashier.aspx</link><pubDate> CST
									</pubDate><category>
										Employment
									</category><guid>http://www.cityoftulsa.org/our-city/jobs/current-openings/part-time,-temporary,-summer-jobs-and-internships/cashier.aspx</guid><description><![CDATA[ Under immediate supervision receives and records payments, assists with fiscal clerical duties, and other related assigned duties.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ 
<p>Position Code:&nbsp; 5120-0008SCG<br />
Performing Arts Center, Ticket Office<br />
Pay Grade:&nbsp; OT-14 / Salary Range:&nbsp; $8.27 - $14.61<br />
<strong>Part time:&nbsp; 10 - 25 hours a week</strong></p>

<p><strong>Essential Job Functions:<br />
</strong>Collects money and checks delivered by mail or directly
from the public<br />
<br />
Posts and verifies receipts, checks and cash<br />
<br />
Refers utility customers to customer service personnel in cases of
incorrect statements<br />
<br />
Reconciles daily receipts<br />
<br />
Prepares daily receipts batches for data processing<br />
<br />
Sells admission tickets at public buildings<br />
<br />
Totals bills, vouchers and cash<br />
<br />
Reasonable accommodations may be made to enable individuals with
disabilities to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Minimum Requirements:<br />
</strong>Graduation from high school or possession of a General
Educational Development Certificate (GED) and two (2) years of
general office experience; or an equivalent combination of training
and experience per Personnel Policies and Procedures, Section
128.</p>

<p>Some knowledge of elementary bookkeeping.&nbsp; Ability to learn
to operate cash registers, validating equipment, adding machines,
calculators, cathode ray tubes, and money changers; and the ability
to understand and influence the behavior of others within the
organization, customers, or the public in order to achieve job
objectives and cause action or understanding.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Requirements:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</strong> Physical requirements include arm and hand steadiness and
finger dexterity enough to use a keyboard and telephone;&nbsp;
occasional lifting and pushing up to 25 pounds;&nbsp; frequent
carrying up to 5 pounds;&nbsp; may be subject to walking, standing,
sitting, reaching, balancing, bending, kneeling, handling,
climbing, and twisting;&nbsp; and vision, speech, and hearing
sufficient to perform the essential tasks.</p>

<p><strong>Licenses and Certificates:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
</strong> None required.</p>

<p><strong>Skills Assessments Required:<br />
</strong>Writing and/or physical skills assessments may be
administered as needed for each position.</p>

<p>Working Environment:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
Working environment is primarily indoors.&nbsp; Part time:&nbsp; 10
- 25 hours a week</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>